Imagine a world where you no longer had to
go out to people to get business.
You didn't have to slide into DMs,
you didn't have to
reach out to people,
you didn't have to be so proactive with
jumping on sales calls
with people.
Imagine a world where all you had to do
was put out an
email, put out a social media post,
put out a carousel, or put out something,
and
those leads come to you. Ultimately,
for the last nine years,
I've come to realize I'm actually a bit of
an introvert.
Right now,
I can give you guys a couple of hours of
my energy to go
through the four pillars,
which we're going to go through, which
is going to be
socials,
then we're going to look at squeeze,
then we're going to look at sales,
then we're going to look at scale.
And I know those can sound pretty unsexy.
Two hours here, fine.
But at the same time of that,
I don't want to be jumping on calls with
people, giving them my energy.
I don't want to be DM-ing strangers
or whatever.
The last eight years,
whether it's been selling the books,
scaling Nutonics to
seven figures a month,
getting over 125,000 people in my fitness
app, I've
never done a sales call.
I've never done outreach.
Back in the day,
I used to do door-to-door sales,
and I used to have to prospect on
a gym floor. And at the age of 26, I
was like, "I'm done." Every
system I'm going to build and create
is going to get leads to come to me.
So over the next, could be an hour,
could be two hours, I don't know,
we're going
to go through all of the systems
that I've put in
that not only have worked for me,
but they've worked for probably close to
2,000 businesses that I work with now.
So it's important that some of you,
when we go through some things,
you'll think,
"Hmm, I actually already knew this."
It's probably important
that we remind you rather than teach you
on some of the
things.
But even if you sit through this for an
hour, and there's only two or three
things that you walk away with,
they will have a massive impact on your
business
over time. So we're going to start at
that top
position of the four S's.
We're going to look into socials.
This is also going to be a hugely
interactive video because again,
first of all,
I've done exactly what I set out to with
the premise of this live.
I've got you guys to come to me for this.
But the second thing is,
I'm not able to read minds.
So I'm not just going to sit here
and lecture you about what I've done for
two
hours.
I'm going to give you a framework that's
going to structure the questions
and the curiosity
that you're going to have back towards me.
And then from that,
we're going to be able to work through it,
challenge me,
disagree with me.
We can even fight on a live stream as far
as you're
concerned or I'm concerned.
There's going to be a link to an offer
that's going to
be pinned in the comments,
and I should have put it in the
description.
We're even going to go through the very
tactics that I've used to get you here on
a
live stream and how I even got this live
stream to look so crisp and sound so great
and everything else like that.
So to begin with,
what I want to start with is that socials.
Some of you might have had apprehensions
in your life.
Oh, do I need to use social media?
Do I really need to put my face out there?
Is there a way that I can grow a brand
or a business without having to be on
social
media? But ultimately,
when you look around, even now on
Netflix,
they're having to make the storylines
of Netflix programs more simple because
they're having to take into account
that people are going to be on their
phones whilst they're watching TV.
And although I know that
is pretty depressing,
it just goes to show where people's
attention is right now.
I am a high-functioning
professional, potentially,
but I'm also a fucking crack addict when
it comes to scrolling on my phone,
when it comes to getting a little bit of a
TikTok five-minute brain rot.
I like to watch fat people falling over on
ice as much as you guys.
So all of us have this addiction.
All of us have this tendency to go to our
phones, whether we're tired, energetic,
bored, whatever it is. So
when we look at an opportunity out there,
it makes
sense that we utilize social media because
people are spending a lot of their time
on there.
And that goes from high-paid professional
CEO family man,
all the way to bricklayers,
all the way to mums
that want to get back into training
postpartum. We're all there.
And the quicker that we can just come
together and
realize we all have this tendency to spend
a lot of time there,
we can get into this a lot quicker.
We're all flawed.
We all have a dopamine reward system
that we're tapping into.
It's an opportunity.
Let's not be sad about it. So
that would be where people are.
The next question in that would be
when. And I think when,
especially recently, is something
that we don't need to
worry about too much, because when is--
before, when the algorithm was time-based,
you would have to say, "Right, okay, my
perfect clientele is going to be on at
8:00 a.m.,
so I'm going to post at 7:45." I
don't think that's as important as it used
to be.
Post-pandemic TikTokification of social
media, I'm
now a believer that, yeah,
it makes sense to post at the right
time, but it's not the end of the world.
Because the algorithm
is now going to score content based upon
what people are
interested in, what they need,
what they would like to see,
and it's going to show
it to them.
A good example of this for any of you
that are active on LinkedIn,
you'll notice now
that maybe 30% to 40% of LinkedIn posts
that you see are over two
weeks old. So where, social media.
When, I don't think it's that important.
We even, with the podcast recently,
and again,
if you have any questions about the
podcast or any of the other marketing
strategies that I'm using at the moment to
grow my businesses,
you put them in the comments,
and we will go through them
shortly. But even with the podcast,
there was a lot of people saying, "Oh, you
need to post at this time.
You need to get these people
when they wake up.
You need to get them for a commute." It
ultimately doesn't matter.
The same on YouTube. YouTube
is going to put everything in front of
people.
Everything's going to put something in
front of people if they're interested
in it. YouTube's not going to say,
"Great video.
An amazing thing that you've done here,
but this person
was online 10 minutes too late,
so we're not going to show it to them." So
when we
look at things like
what time,
let's not worry about it too much.
That I don't think is a priority.
I think where people are
is a lot more important than
when they're online.
Then the most important thing here
that I think people still have issues with
is who. And when we talk about who,
we're talking about who
is it we're talking to.
I think that probably one of the biggest
issues that people face with people that I
work with is who is my niche? Who
is it that I'm working with?
Who is it that I'm talking to?
And I do feel that a lot of you have been
oversold the niche game, that even I
have disputes with people in my Discord,
even last night
Someone was saying,
"Oh,
this is how to lose weight for over 40s."
And I was like,
"Why do that?
Why segment it to just the over 40s?"
Because ultimately,
if someone's 39, is
that advice not going to work for them?
Well, no,
it's probably going to work for them.
Then shut up, don't put it in there.
And they said, "Well,
how can I get people to engage in my
content and watch my
YouTube videos?" I was like, "Well,
take that out the title
and just make the video
better." If you make the video good
and people watch through it,
and people enjoy
it, and people get value from it,
it's going to be shown to a much wider
audience.
Trying to segment your title to a certain
demographic of age, to me, is just
a little bit stupid. But again,
we're going to get into all of this.
But the first kind of actionable point for
any of you out there, there are going to
be some of you watching this have got a
pen and paper at the ready.
Now, whenever I say this,
I know people don't do it,
but you should do it anyway,
whether it's notes on your phone,
notes on your laptop,
pen and paper, whatever it is,
just start writing down 20
problems throughout this whole life
that your ideal client faces.
And what you'll realize
is actually making notes of problem--
If I said to you, "Do
you know your clients' problems?" You're
like, "Yeah.
Yeah, of course, I do." "Okay,
give me 20." And you're, "Oh,
shit." It's quite
difficult. Now, you could be a wills
and a probate lawyer, you could be an
accountant,
you could be an exercise physiologist,
you could be a personal trainer,
you could be any of these things.
But ultimately, often, the more
problems that you can plot down in front
of someone, the easier this whole
socials level of the four S's
is going to get.
So everything is going to be reverse
engineered from a problem.
Even this live stream,
if we think about it, I sat there
and thought, "Hmm,
what would work well in organic
and paid to attract people to want to come
into a
live?" And I thought, the problem is
that people are having to spend energy and
time
and a bit of mental health going after
leads.
They're having to try
and cold DM 100 people a day,
they're having to jump on sales
calls.
So I reverse engineer the problem to even
make this live here today.
So if you can write down 20 of those
things,
it's going to benefit you massively.
There's also an exercise
that I've been getting people to do for
the last year that
I'll tell you straight. So
if someone's put up three or
four rubbish titles for a YouTube video,
if I can sniff a
bit of ChatGPT, I get really annoyed.
I'm like,
"A lot of you have been fed a lie,
I'm sorry to say it,
that ChatGPT is this amazing thing,
that it's great and it's going to ideate,"
and
it's just not the case. If you
were to write a course, or you
were to write a
script,
or you were to write a video that's
8,000 words,
and you put it into ChatGPT and you say,
"Am I missing something?"
It could very well go, "Hey,
why don't you talk about this?" You go,
"Fucking hell.
That's a great idea."
And you could say to ChatGPT, "Okay,
can you give me some
rough talking points
that I should have for
that component?" And it will do it.
But when you get ChatGPT to ideate your
titles and your video ideas or whatever
it is, they just look shit.
And we can see this on LinkedIn again.
Any of those you using LinkedIn,
it's so easy to spot AI being utilized for
people's
ideation, copy, scripts.
I can even see it on people's landing
pages.
Now,
this is the kind of tinfoil hat moment
that I'm going to give you all.
Has it ever occurred to you
that loads of your competitors
are telling you, or
actually loads of people in the space
anyway,
are saying you must use AI because it
makes your content shitter?
I'm just going to throw this out there,
okay?
If I sit here and tell hundreds of
personal trainers on a live stream, "Hey,
guys,
use ChatGPT to come up with your titles,
your ideation, your hooks, your
set-ups,
your pay-offs," I'm actually dumbing down
all of your creativity, and I'm
holding you back two years.
It's like getting held back a year in
school.
ChatGPT to me is like a
member of staff who's on £22,000 a year.
You get them to do some of your admin
work, but you do not get them to do the
important stuff.
So yeah, that's one of the things
that I think is quite important for this.
So yeah, don't
think to yourself, "Okay,
I've got a good idea.
Let's go put it on ChatGPT
and it's going to make it better." It's
not.
So the exercise that I give people is say,
"Give me 20, 30," or sometimes
I even say,
"Give me 40 different titles to this
YouTube
video." And people go,
"That's ridiculous." They go,
"That's crazy." Same way when
I said write down 20 problems.
And what ends up happening is you start
ideating the titles,
and you get four good ones,
then you get four shit ones,
then you get three that
are kind of a bit too short,
then three that are a bit too
long. Then when you get to 15, 20, 25, you
start going into this flow state of title
ideation, and you come up with some
quirky ones and some funky ones.
Then often at fucking title
26, you're like, "Wow,
that slaps." So a lot of this
pen and paper shit
that I'm talking about right now is that
often there are a lot of ideas
and concepts in your head
that need to be fleshed
out, and there are problems
that you may not have even realized
are in your
head. I had another personal trainer,
what, yesterday, send me his content,
and his video that he spoke about
was actually a bit boring.
It's kind of like a recovery protocol
thing.
And he just glossed over the fact. He
was like, "Things you wouldn't take when
you're injured, anti-inflammatories."
And I was like, "Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa."
I was like, "Mate,
you inside a pretty average video just
told people that they shouldn't be taking
anti-inflammatories when they've got a
rolled ankle,
when the majority of people think they
need to take
anti-inflammatories." I was like,
"You getting 5,000 views on your video
just
skipped over a concept that's usually a
million views." And it's because he
hadn't realized that's a problem
that people face.
So again, those problems
that you can understand from your
demographic are integral for you to ideate
not just content, but think about this.
That list of problems
is going to help you ideate content.
Twenty problems is going to give you 10
pieces of content.
Out of those 10 pieces of content,
one of them is going to do way better than
everything else.
You probably take your top three pieces of
content, remake them
two or three times,
and you're now building evidence into what
it is your audience
are interested in.
The next stage from that,
which we're going to get onto in a
second,
would then be the next S in the four S's,
which would be the squeeze, and
you would use that content or problem
or ideation to get someone's data from
them.
But let's not jump ahead.
I hope you guys are all getting this in.
Again, any questions, they go in the box.
So
when we were talking about the caveat of
when we post, one thing I have seen,
again, we'll talk about LinkedIn.
I've grown to nearly 30,000 on there in
the last few months.
It's a surprising platform because some
days I do just get like
$1,000,
$1,500 of business of people buying stuff
from my
coaching app.
I'm now using tracking links all across my
kind of
advertising sphere.
I wouldn't say I've nailed it yet, but
LinkedIn does remain quite dormant at
weekends and out of hours.
That is probably the only platform
that I would say needs to be used in work
hours.
So that when, not so important.
What, we spoke about the problems there.
Hopefully, you guys have got a list of it.
The next thing we want to delve into a
little bit more is who is it we
are talking
to. Now,
the most important lesson
that I can give you on this is, it is so
much better for us to cast a net that
is too wide
than too niche. Too wide than too niche.
We've all seen that fitness chick on the
internet.
"Hey, lesbians,
if you're looking to lose weight." So by
saying, "Hey,
lesbians," she's got total addressable
market.
She cut it in half by insinuating
that they're female, then the amount of
those that are lesbians is even smaller.
Now, I get it, she's probably gay,
cool,
but trying to segment her market into
utilizing sexuality is just daft.
She has just reduced the amount of people
that can do business with her massively.
Same way that a lot of people in their
content try to appear
smart,
or they try to appeal to authority by
using big words, and all you're doing
is shrinking a total addressable market.
And those of you using short-form content,
it's very important you understand this,
your video, quite crudely,
is just going to get thrown to 100 people,
maybe even
1,000 people, and the algorithm
is going to react to how those
people found it. So
if you're going to make a video
about patellar tendonitis,
you do need to ask yourself,
how many people,
out of a random 100 people,
have got patellar tendonitis?
Because if it's 1%, even if
that 1% person goes, "Oh my God,
this is the best video I've ever seen on
patellar tendonitis," the other 99% of
people signal a very quick scroll away.
So rather than the algorithm listening to
what your post is about, it's listening
to what other people
are doing with the reaction to it.
So first of all, not to over-niche,
don't go
too narrow. I'd rather we started wider,
then people can find their way out as
they move down the four S's.
Because you might appeal to everyone in
content,
then your lead magnet starts pushing
people out,
and then your offer starts pushing
people out. There
are places for people to leave the funnel.
Don't make it the very first place
that we go with it.
All right. That would be the next thing.
Ideal client. So everyone out there,
we should have an ideal client.
My two were Susan Green and Jackie Smith.
They're my favorite clients.
They were slightly older. They
were both married.
They were coming to the gym during day
hours.
They both had disposable income. They
were both in a position where I
then ended up training their husbands,
and I already kind of knew that the
relationship with them was a bit like...
Their husbands probably wouldn't have
liked me until their wife said, "Look,
he's a
bit of a mouthy fucker, but come in,
meet him, and you'll like
him." So all of the content I did for the
first few years was always trying to
appeal to Susan Green and Jackie Smith.
So all of you guys out there should have
your favorite clients in mind.
I would say to use
that as your avatar to begin with.
Because some of you out there are, "Oh,
I just really want to work with athletes,"
or,
"I really want to work with FTSE 100
businesses, or
companies in the S&P 500."
But then your favorite clients are those
small niche businesses with a team of 10.
What you want for a perfect environment
for your work
is that you can replicate your favorites
because they are your favorites for
a reason. It is the working experience
and relationship that you have with
them. So a lot of the time,
when it comes to our avatar, who we
are talking to in
content, the easiest,
lowest hanging fruit for this
is to go after
people that are the same as your favorite
client. Hope that makes sense.
So,
we're going to quickly get onto
the next segment, which
is going to be squeeze.
But whilst we're in this content area,
I've got a course called Black Belt
Content
Mastery, and the reason
that I called it Black Belt is this.
You want to become
a black belt in this.
If you want to become a black belt in
jujitsu, it's going to
take you 10 years, and it's going to suck,
and you're going to probably snap a few
tendons or whatever.
But becoming a content black belt
is actually
relatively easy in comparison.
And think of it this way.
When you are a black belt in jujitsu,
almost every room you go into,
you should beat the majority of people.
Maybe there's one or two other people
that you can't beat, but that's fine.
Every person, every room you go into,
you should very
successfully be able to beat everyone.
Cool.
But here's the interesting thing.
The people that you don't beat,
the other black belts,
you have this shared respect
for each other, and
that shared respect means you trade
industry secrets with each
other. Some of you may not know,
but gyms around the world let other black
belts
train for free. So what I'm saying
is this.
If you make it to a black belt in content
creation through thousands of hours of
repetition, loads of videos that bomb,
loads of videos that do well, whatever it
is,
you will start to sound very confident.
You might think that I'm a good presenter.
I wasn't.
I've just done this for years
and years on end.
But if you can walk into a room
surrounded of other people
and come out on top as a black belt,
that's what we want
to do in content. Whatever you're doing,
if you are a wills and probate lawyer,
we're going to make you the black belt so
you can beat everyone in the room.
If you are the accountant, if you
are the exercise physiologist, if you
are the
physio, the more competent you are...
And the reason that I can beat people in
jujitsu is because of all the hours of
work and failing I've done before.
Let's not look over that.
But the crazy thing is,
now other people with big followings or
big social media accounts, or people
that are good at content, we sit there,
and we
just talk about what's worked,
what hasn't,
and it allows you to level up quicker.
So let's get into some questions you guys
have now.
You can challenge me on the concept of
becoming a black belt.
We can talk about the audience,
the avatar, the socials,
the importance of it,
whatever it is.
I've got some here to the side. Auggie.
In Dubai,
you taught me to read fiction to get
better at email marketing and
writing emails.
What else would you say would help getting
leads on the list from
cold to warm? Okay.
Some people are just going to take a lot
of emails, for a start.
That's just the case of it. So right now,
you're looking at the
second component, second
and third component.
We've got squeeze,
which would be getting their data,
and we've got sell, which
would be the third S there.
So we've got two components here
that we could
double down on. Now,
I would say reading fiction books,
and for any of you that
don't understand this,
a fiction author just has one job in a
book,
and it's to get you to turn the next page.
It's just to get you to keep reading.
And actually, although some of you think,
"I don't really like reading," if a
fiction author can drag a point out for
ages on end, you
actually love it. Any of you
that have watched "Pluribus" online,
have you noticed
that, what's his name, Vince Gilligan
or whatever his name is, the creator of
"Breaking Bad," he drags out the same
scene for so long because it builds
suspense.
So that's ultimately what we're trying to
do in email marketing.
So I would say, one,
keep getting good at writing emails,
but two, I
would fuck both ways.
I would use your emails to fuck down to
get
sales, but again,
above the email marketing,
so from stage two,
go back up to stage one, create
more long-form content,
put out more things that can help people.
Because when I'm on your email list,
it's not just your email list that's going
to
help me convert.
Now I'm on your email list,
I've signaled to you that I'm
interested,
but more helpful content in the layer
above is going to
help. But
getting them from cold to warm,
be relatable, be consistent, try
and email them all the time.
There's going to be so many days where
they're just going to be having a shit,
your
email comes through,
and you just put a smile on their face.
So that's what I would say for that.
Okay, Jill Cookson. "I find ChatGPT
is good dumping ground for all ideas.
It helps give structure,
make other observations,
and I use it as a virtual partner
to capture, breakdown, and refine.
Why is that a wrong approach?" I didn't
say it's a wrong approach because you've
just said that you're giving ChatGPT all
the information, and you're just telling
it to restructure it. But the issue is,
if you say to, "Give
me 10 ideas on fat loss
that I can make on Instagram," the ideas
are dog shit.
So you just said it's a good dumping
ground for all
ideas. This means the ideas
are coming from you.
So yeah, it could give you structure,
it can make observations, it can do other
stuff like that. What I'm saying is,
don't use it to determine what
you make content about. Because
if you assume that ChatGPT is going to
know the problems
that your client faces better than you,
it's not.
And also,
ChatGPT just draws off all the data that's
already there.
So anything novel or original
is just not going to make it to the
forefront of
whatever that gives you.
Jim Jitsu, "I'm a BJJ black belt.
How shall I grow a YouTube channel focused
on
beginners?"
Again, I would reframe what you say there.
How should I grow a YouTube channel
focused on solving problems?
Now, you shouldn't say,
"BJJ for beginners." You shouldn't.
You should say things like,
"How to sweep from half guard,
how to escape side
control,
how to get heavy people off you in mount,
how to defend my back when it's
taken." You actually want to talk to the
problems of a beginner.
You don't want to talk to beginners.
What you don't want to do is go, "Hey,
beginners in jujitsu, watch this." Because
although some people might resonate with
it, you want to say, "How to get higher
belts off your back in training."
And they go, "Wow, do you know what?
Last night,
I just had a fucking blue belt
or purple belt kill me from
behind." Then in the introduction to your
video, you say, "Isn't it annoying when
you've worked really hard,
you've learned a few moves in training,
then suddenly a
high belt takes your back
and you feel powerless?
Well, good news is,
there's actually three different ways out
from the back, and I
guarantee that high belt that's beating
you up doesn't even know one of them.
So in this video,
we're going to go through three ways to
escape the back so that
higher belts will absolutely hate you in
training." So again, your
channel just becomes fixated
and focused on solving problems for
jujitsu athletes, not beginners.
And when you get a finger on the pulse of
solving those problems, people resonate
with it.
Then after you've done those three
problems, you could say to people,
"Oh, by the way,
I've put together a system
that helps you tap higher belts.
If you want it,
click the link in the description
or whatever." Because you've got
to think and you've got to psychologically
get on the frame of what beginners want.
As a beginner,
I don't want to learn things.
I want to tap purple belts.
That's what I want to do.
And I may not say it out loud because, oh,
it's
professor.
So just think about all those things
that you had when you were younger
and try and tap into them.
That's what I would say anyway.
Okay.
Dude Lucas,
"I need strategies on lead conversions.
I've got traffic to my Instagram,
but struggling to actually get followers
to
customers." We're going to move to
that next.
So
some people that I work with have got
their socials pumping.
So that first layer, that first S
is doing really well,
but then nothing happens
below it.
That's why I've split this into the four
S's, socials, squeeze,
sales, scale.
So we're going to get into that very,
very quickly.
Katrina,
"Is it good to put heaps of content out on
social and see what lands?" That's
ultimately what you do.
Have you ever noticed, right?
If we were to look at paid ads, and
if we look at those four sections,
paid ads
would sit at top of funnel with socials.
Because if you're paying to be in front of
someone, unless you've got their data,
you haven't moved down. So
when you run ads, advertising teams will
get hundreds,
if not thousands of creatives.
They'll spread it across,
and they'll look to see
which ad performs the best.
And then the ads
that don't perform the best,
you reign back advertising budget.
The ads that are performing the best,
you give more budget.
It's the exact same thing you do with
content.
And how do you know in the beginning?
You don't.
The only way you can get feedback
is through doing it.
Had a bit of a, not a falling out.
Let's have a stern word with someone in
the
mentorship yesterday where you have kind
of paralysis.
I've got other coaches now in my
mentorship that help me out.
So Ollie is my YouTube strategist,
and whenever he's quiet,
I might help people out
in the Discord. Then we got Cam. Now,
Cam was actually a
member of the mentorship. He
was giving really good feedback,
and he's helped two
massive people in the fitness industry
grow their YouTube and their socials and
whatever. Now, Cam
and I don't just fucking echo each other
like
parrots. And someone asked a question,
Cam gave his input, and my input was
slightly different.
So this guy comes to me over email, and
he's a bit
emotionally sensitive to the fact
that he got two different bits of
feedback from two different people.
And I said, "Hey, bro, for a start,
if you want us all to give you the same
fucking feedback, what's the point in
having a coaching team?" I said, "Second,
maybe Cam's right, maybe I'm
right. The only way to figure it out is
if you go both make
fucking videos. Go make them both,
come back, let us
know." Because we are giving you
An idea of what we think would work based
on our own experiences.
Cam's experience is different to mine,
but the only person with the keys to the
castle knowing what's going to fucking
work is you, bro.
So I was like, "Go make it,
and let's see." Because
at the end of the day,
the only way you can do it is to test
and find out.
Jay Sims Coaching,
"How frequently should you be sending
emails?"
Think of it this way.
[lips smack] The area
that the emails sit in
is probably going to be the cell.
It's probably going to be the third S,
right?
If I was posting social media on content,
trying to win your business, would every
day be okay? You'd be like, "Yeah,
every day is fine." Cool.
If I was trying to grow my email list,
how often should I do it?
Is every day okay?
Yeah, cool. With email marketing,
I just find that when I hit people every
day,
things do better. Everything does better.
It's momentum, it's showing up,
it's caring.
It's also what a lot of my competitors
won't do.
So December, maybe 16th, things
are slowing down,
it's December. I pre-wrote 10 emails,
and they went out to every single
person on my email list,
and I email people on Christmas Eve,
Christmas
Day, Boxing Day, I didn't give a shit.
We hit one of our probably fifth biggest
months ever in December, purely based off
those emails that I pre-wrote.
And I didn't write them on Christmas Eve,
I
pre-wrote them days before. Now,
think of it this way,
if you're trying to get
someone to win over their business,
can you be in contact with them too much?
Because ultimately,
if you're trying to help them,
which you are, if you're a
coaching business,
you want to help someone lose weight,
you don't want to just turn up once a
week.
And I'm going to throw this out there as
well.
Any of you that get Chris Williamson's
emails, they're long.
And sometimes I'll look into it
and I'll go, "Bro,
you could have split this up and
put this in three emails." And
if I said to you guys, what would you
rather do? Would you rather read a
60-second email three times
or have a three-minute email once?
I know what you like, you're ADHD fucks.
So I like to go daily as an approach,
because also think of it this way,
if I'm hitting people over Christmas
daily, there's going to be a day
that you lose
three clients in a day
and you'll feel like the world's falling
out from underneath
you. Boom, I'm in your email inbox,
and I'm telling you to, "Come here,
brother.
I can help you." So I will always lean
towards daily.
I also think that email lists I've been on
where I get hit daily have just
converted me better.
Ben H.,
"What's the best way to set up an email
marketing strategy?" We're going to
get into that next. Thomas, "Are PDFs bad,
outdated for lead magnets?
What do you recommend instead for 2026 as
a physiotherapist and PT?"
Okay, PDFs, right?
The issue that I have with them is
if you're going to write an e-book,
can you see the completion rate of that?
So for instance, it might be all well
and good, you seeing, oh yeah, I've got
1,000 people to read my PDF. But
if it's 18 pages long and people just
skim it and they never read it, fine.
I've downloaded loads of PDFs.
I can never tell you one that I finished.
I go, "Oh, this looks nice." Boom, gone.
Then when I get an offer from that person,
I think, "Bro, I couldn't even finish
your PDF, brother.
So why am I going to pay you for coaching
if I couldn't even get
through the fucking free e-book you sent?"
The next issue with that
is e-books, right?
I'll spend a year writing these
and people don't finish them.
That is literally a year of my life
that I've gone and I've been paid
heavy six figures to get those, right?
So I'm putting a lot of effort into it.
Even they're hard to sell.
They'll sometimes be on Amazon for $4.99
and still people won't read them. So
when you put together an e-book in an
afternoon in a cafe
and you put it together
and you think people are going to froth
over it, there's just
that component to it.
I think there are better ways to do it,
and we'll get into it in the squeeze
section. But the issue
is you're looking at something
that's very easy for you,
but it's not easy for them.
Because for you, you go, "Yeah,
I'll spend seven hours
putting together an e-book."
But you haven't thought about the other
person.
Does the other person really want to spend
45 minutes reading your e-book
that you just whipped together?
Probably not.
So there is one PDF that I send out,
which is my landing
page template, but even that
is actually a Trojan horse.
So my highly converting sales page lead
magnet gives you a visual
representation,
then everything follows up with emails,
and you get about 11 emails
afterwards. So
not mad on PDFs if I'm honest.
Last question,
then we'll move on to the next part.
Okay, we've got two.
What tips would you give someone starting
off struggling to
grow their Instagram? All right.
You've done this here, Gary.
You've said you're struggling to grow your
Instagram. I'm going to go on it.
All right, let's have a little look.
Gary Bailey,
8166.
All right. Let's have a little look.
Gary Bailey, 8166.
I can't even find you, mate.
All right. That's not your Instagram,
is it, Gary? Give us your Instagram.
Let's get it out there in front of
everyone. All right. Gazza.
Gary Bailey. Let's have a look.
Let me see if I can find you.
I found Gary Bailey, 85,
but I'm struggling to find you, bro.
So this could be an issue.
Gary Bailey.
Yeah,
give us that because we're going to look
into that because I guarantee you
give me 10 seconds to look at your page,
I'll tell you exactly what it is.
Okay, last one. Shamone23. Is
that like Shamone?
Dude with ADHD here.
I'm 10-year experienced osteopath.
Pretty fucking good.
The issue I have is
that boasting on social media makes me
cringe to death.
Any tips for getting over this? Brother,
no one was ever told,
or you weren't supposed to be boasting on
social
media. What are you supposed to be doing?
What do you do as an osteopath?
You help people, right?
And how do you help people?
You help people through solving their
problems of
back pain or whatever it is.
I'm not actually 100% sure what osteopathy
does or means or whatever.
So the thing you want to be
doing is in fact helping people because
those problems that people come to you
with, someone comes into your office
and sits down and goes,
"Oh, I've got a real problem here."
And you go, "Well, actually,
it's because you
sit cross-legged and your left leg's..."
I'm making this up, "...
under the right leg all the time." So you
say you've been doing this 10 years,
right?
And I don't understand why you told me
you've got ADHD
So you've been doing this 10 years,
you've worked with thousands of people,
and you
think social media is for boasting, right?
So you've got clients
that have come in
and you've said you're pretty fucking
good.
So if you're pretty fucking good at
something, you've helped people, and
if you
help people, they've got problems.
If they've got problems,
you fucking solve them.
And out of all the thousands of people
with problems that you've solved, you're
concerned about not knowing what to post
on social media.
Do you understand how
that can be pretty fucking stupid, bro?
So,
what was the last client victory you had?
Now, don't boast about it.
Instead,
is that person the only person on the
planet that's got that fucking
issue? Highly doubt it.
So why not turn that into a content piece
to help other
people with it? As a
therapist,
let's imagine you have a client who comes
in
and you work on some visualization
techniques or some reframing techniques or
whatever, and they go, "This has really,
really, really helped me." Cool.
You could then go out to social media
and go, "If you're struggling with this
client problem, then here
are some techniques
that we use in practice to help
people." Explain the solution.
Okay.
I think I might have found your account,
Gary.
Is it Gary Bailey Motivation?
I'm going to reckon it is.
You've got 14,000 followers,
which isn't bad.
Let me see if the camera's going to pick
that up.
Probably won't because I've got a bit of
an expensive setup going on.
Now, if this is you,
there's no bloody bio.
There's no information here about
anything. Confirm that this is you.
14,000 followers.
Let's get into it. We'll get into it.
But anyway,
we've got some stuff to do here, mate.
I'm afraid we'll have to come back to
that. We've got things to get into.
We're going to get into some content
things now.
We're going to try
and find Gary on the live,
and we're going to go into a
questions segment in about five minutes.
So hold tight.
We're going to go through a bit of basic
stuff before we get to the squeeze just on
this.
There'll be some people out there that
are embarrassed to ask very, very
basic questions. So first things,
dimensions.
You can shoot in portrait or landscape.
Landscape is going to be for YouTube.
Landscape,
I do think works a bit better on LinkedIn.
Everything else is going to be portrait.
Now, good news is,
when you film landscape,
let's say you were to film a YouTube
video, you can crop in.
So you can essentially,
even if you watch right now,
either side of me, we could cut out
and we've got a
reel. Now, some platforms
that you guys could use for this,
there's a platform
called Opus Pro, and what you do
is you film a YouTube video, you take your
YouTube URL, you chuck it in Opus,
O-P-U-S.pro,
and it will clip it up for you.
Are all the clips good?
No, but it's a low barrier to entry.
And actually, all of the reels
that you see
on the James Smith business Instagram
are actually put through Opus.
And then what you can do
is you can actually get a bit of a team
member to go through
and repost those for you.
So I'll be honest,
I actually don't post those clips to
Instagram.
Someone else does it.
So that's one thing
that I've kind of put off.
Next thing to consider, iPhone cameras.
Now, there has been a bit of a movement,
especially with the new iPhones, that
these front cameras are getting very good.
If you look at people like Adam Sullivan,
they're just pointing and shooting a lot.
I'm enjoying these,
and I'm going to start doing it a lot more
myself.
I think now we've moved into a realm where
if you have an idea and you don't have
the luxury of filming, scripting,
whatever, just hit record,
talk to your phone,
get it out there.
Because although the chances of a front
camera
video getting 10 million views are slim,
it's frequency, it's
posting. And again,
you might only get 3,000 views on a video,
but that could be
enough to get a lead.
I was fitting an exhaust on my car.
I said to the guy doing it, I go, "Bro,
you're probably getting a booking every
views." So,
if you do a video about Coke Zero,
you might get 100,000 views. But
are you getting anyone to book in?
No one's going, "Write my workouts,
bro," because you did a video on Coke
Zero.
But if you did a video on a certain
specific topic, even
if you just shoot your
phone or whatever,
could it potentially bring in a lead?
Then fucking post it.
That's just as simple as it goes.
As far as the phone cameras as well,
the zooms behind them, this zoom
thing is quite important. So
if you watched the last webinar that we
did, I look better in this one.
And the reason I look better is
that is a 50 mil. The last one, I think,
was a 35.
So every lens has to have a certain amount
of width to it.
So the fisheye lens, your wide,
have you noticed
that everything looks shit in a
wide? The reason for that being
is you're letting all of this information
in from a wide angle, and
that distorts the image a bit.
So that's why girls hate it
when you take a picture with a
wide in front of them.
It's also why you look better on the back
camera than the
front camera. So if you can,
the camera that's here actually
is probably about a
meter away from me because we're using a
50.
If you can,
move the phone a bit further away,
use a bit more zoom, and you'll look
better because it's not letting in so much
information from a wider outside
picture.
That's a little hack for you guys to use.
The front camera has to be wide,
and it has to be low quality because it's
on the
front.
So anytime you have the opportunity to use
the back camera, please do.
And the zoom kind of thing,
just think the more you zoom,
the better it's going to
look.
But you don't want your phone a million
miles away.
A lot of you are now thinking, "Oh,
but James, then how can I see
if I'm in frame?"
If you plug this into your computer with
USB-C and you go to QuickTime,
you can look like a
movie of what's on your phone.
So you can move your tripod around,
and you can make
sure that you're in frame,
and then you can hit record,
and you can record yourself
through QuickTime or on your phone
and use that as a preview.
So the cameras that you use is going to be
pretty important.
So as far as filming,
I think where before I would say let's use
a
camera,
I'd say now we're moving into a realm of
where iPhone is making it
a lot easier for us to use it to just pick
up, shoot, and go.
And again, think of it this way.
If you're new to this,
you could make four videos a day low
quality, or one video a day
high quality, maybe, let's just say.
I'd rather you did four low-quality
videos.
And again, I didn't say shit,
I said low quality.
Because then we get a faster amount of
feedback to determine what it is our
audience are interested in,
because then we can layer it back.
Because ultimately,
even though we're experts,
we must think about fingering.
And what I mean by this is this.
You can be the biggest shagger in the
world. You can know the anatomy of a human
vagina all you like, human woman's vagina.
Sorry, us women.
But ultimately,
everyone's a little bit different
when it comes to the finger bash.
Some people might like feeding the pony,
some might like the come to me, some might
like the swim up, whatever it is.
So the only way you're going to know is
to finger. So what I'm saying by that
is you're never really going to
know what your audience
is into until you start bashing the
keypad.
So you start putting stuff out there,
and then you can be receptive to that
audience. I never knew.
I posted for years without swearing
because I
thought people would hate it if I swore.
Turns out I was wrong.
Okay,
just before we get into the squeeze
element, which is going to be important,
we're just going to look into video
structure.
I'm going to break it down
and probably use some crass analogies for
this.
Hooks,
and everyone's got these real complex
fucking
ideas about what a hook is. The hook
is the first thing we say in content.
Now, for us to really understand hooks,
I need you to think about this.
I'm in bed with my missus. It's 9:00 PM,
we're going to bed in half an
hour.
My job is to get as much fucking [growls]
dopamine and brain rot into my body as
possible. So I'm there in bed doing this.
[tapping] People are lucky
if they get a second.
Boring, boring, boring, boring.
Your dog's ugly. Boring.
I'm doing that.
So our hook,
let's not think about the elevator hook
and someone
getting their attention before they leave.
Let's just think about this.
Can I, in three seconds,
get you interested?
That's it.
So again, the Coke Zero reel.
Does Coke Zero give you cancer?
That's a question hook.
And I only know it's a question hook
because I was
listening to it back and I was like,
"It's a question hook." So then all the
people
that have heard that in under three
seconds can make a decision whether or not
they're interested. If I know the answer,
gone.
But if it's something
that has curiosity in my mind,
something that I'm thinking
about,
I'm now going to wait to listen to the
next section.
So the way it works is hook.
Am I interested? Yes. No. No? Gone.
Now, by being clear with your hook,
it's fine if a lot of people leave,
because
it's better to have some people to stay
than everyone to leave.
If you labor your point, you're too slow,
or even you don't respect the amount of
time that someone has in front of them,
they're going to leave.
So the hook is very, very important.
Now, if the hook does well,
they'll move to the setup.
Let's not get away from that.
There's a statement hook,
and I know this isn't a Coke Zero, this
is a can of
Nutonic, which is much better.
Everything you know about Coke Zero
is a lie.
That's a statement hook.
So again,
the statement hook builds curiosity.
What's a lie?
Is it about the calories?
Is it about the sugar content?
Is it about the aspartame?
What is it?
Then we could even go with a preview hook.
I'm making these up, by the way.
So a preview hook is, let's imagine
I'm going to be talking about protein in a
video, and then a minute into the
video,
I dry scoop a massive bit of protein
powder into my mouth and I gag on it
[coughs] and a cloud of protein powder
comes out.
I could take that
and put it to the beginning.
There is a trend called subtle
foreshadowing that does that,
and basically what I
do is I show that cloud of protein powder
coming out of my mouth.
Then I go to the hook.
But as they're reading
or listening to the hook, they've
suddenly just seen the cloud of protein
powder and they want to know what's
coming.
Another idea of a preview hook
is a trailer. Right?
The beginning of the podcast that I do,
we show what's to come because that is
going to tie people in to build their
interest.
And that could be like a trailer hook,
a preview hook, whatever you want to call
it.
You can have any single type of hook
that you
want if it works.
Now it's just important
that you don't do things
that really fucking shut people
off.
I speak about this all the time,
but any of you that watch CarWow in the
UK, which
is a car motoring channel,
every video starts with a hook.
What wins in a drag race between a
Lamborghini
SVJ and a McLaren 720 LP?
Straight away, we know what the video
is about.
It's not going to be about Ferraris.
It's not going to be about how to do an
oil change.
It's going to be about what wins in a
video between those.
So in your content, whatever subject it
is you're going to talk about,
we just need
to put a hook in.
You might even notice
that I began this live stream with a hook.
Imagine a world where you didn't have to
go get clients and they came to you,
which is technically more of a set-up
because people would have clicked on the
video. But the very first thing
that I said was thought about and it was
strategized because the majority of people
are going to leave in the beginning.
So how can I say this?
If you're going to make a 10-minute video
and each minute
takes you an hour,
I would rather you spent six hours doing
the first minute,
four hours doing the next nine.
The beginning of a video is so important.
If you ever look at any of my YouTube
videos, if there's any animations or
graphics,
we only put them in the first 30 seconds
because they're very time
intensive.
They take Declan a long time,
and I would rather
that he did them in a period
where people are making a decision whether
they're staying or not.
With the hooks,
we can have some visual stuff.
You'll notice some people sit into frame.
Oh, you'll never guess what just happened.
Some people use visuals, props, analogies.
Dr. Julie,
this lip balm represents your mental
health, and this
is what happens
when you listen to Eddie Abu.
So the visuals are very, very important,
especially in that realm of trying to get
people to understand things.
Props are massive, especially in
that therapy, mental health space.
Very, very good. And then hooks and props,
they kind of come through
phases. There was
that fitness phase where everyone had a
blob of fat and a blob of
muscle. They come and go. Okay,
so every single video you have,
you just need to think about the hook.
You need to think about helping people
establish what it is they're getting
into in under three seconds.
This is your muscles,
and this is your muscles on creatine.
You get what I'm saying?
And yes,
I've got three cans of Nutonic here.
I don't know how long we're going for,
brother.
I might even take a Waze under the desk.
Who knows?
So the next part after a hook
is a set-up And what I want you to think
about with
the setup, real simple is,
if I'm still here, I'm interested.
So tell me more.
So
does Coke Zero give you cancer? Hook.
70% of people don't care,
30% of people do care.
The next thing I need to say is,
"Well,
I broke down all the ingredients in Coke
Zero to
find out whether or not this claim
is in fact true."
So then someone at this point
is still making a decision of whether
or not they
want to continue. Someone goes, "Oh,
I don't really care about the
ingredients."
They're going to leave. Other people go,
"Go on." "Well, a lot of people don't
realize that the main sweetener in Coke
Zero is aspartame."
Cool.
That's broken down into three chemicals
called phenylalanine, methanol,
whatever, aspartic acid.
Then we move to a visual,
we move to something else.
This is the setup. Now, the payoff of
that video would be,
you can actually have this many cans
and it's safe for you,
and you can actually
have 10 times this amount
and you're completely fine.
That's the real juice that people wanted.
That's where they go, "Oh, Coke Zero
is not going to give me cancer."
If we get this format wrong,
it messes the whole video up.
If we take the payoff
and use it as a hook,
this is how many cans of Coke Zero
that you could have without getting
cancer.
Cool. See you. Bye. Gone.
I've got the payoff.
If we just go straight to the payoff,
does Coke Zero give you cancer?
Well, actually, this
is the amount of cans
that you could have in a day while
staying safe. Then you go to the setup.
These are the ingredients in Coke Zero.
You're like,
"I would've already got the information,
mate.
I'm gone." So again, in CarWow,
it will go hook, what wins in a drag
race, SVJ, McLaren.
Then the next segment will go through the
information of the
cars, four-wheel drive, two-wheel drive,
rear engine, front engine, horsepower,
torque, all of those.
Then you have the drag race.
But if they did the drag race earlier on
in the video, you wouldn't stay to find
out all the specifications of the cars.
See where I'm going with this?
So we have a hook to let people know
if they're interested,
a setup where we build
up the point and give them the
information.
We also, if we do the setup right,
the person watching
is going to anticipate what
we're going to say.
The payoff either confirms their beliefs
or educates them.
Then we have call to actions. And again,
any questions about this, get them in.
We'll go through them in about two
minutes.
The call to action does not belong in
every video because every video,
what we're
doing,
is we're looking to accrue goodwill.
For instance, we are what?
44 minutes into this video,
and I've not told you to click the link in
the
description.
I've not told you to click the link in the
comments.
I need to earn your trust,
and I'm probably going to wait another 15
minutes
before I even talk about a sales pitch,
or even talk about joining my mentorship,
or talk about the offer.
The reason being is I'm here right now
accruing
goodwill. I want you to think,
"Fucking hell,
this guy knows his stuff." And we
need to do this on social media all the
time.
It is only once we've accrued loads
and loads and loads of goodwill through
turning
up and putting out really,
really helpful content for people
that eventually when
you go,
"Can I get your email address?" You go,
"Go on.
Go on then." You ever had like...
I don't know about you,
I was a bit of a fat loser as a kid,
and there'd be a time that I'd ask out a
girl,
and they wouldn't really be interested.
And then you keep trying for a bit,
not in a creepy way, and then you're like,
"Come on, let's go for a drink."
And they're like, "Oh, fucking hell,
go on then."
And then you end up dating them for four
months, and it's amazing.
So sometimes you do just need to be a
little bit persistent with that,
but you've just got to prove your worth
and your value.
So quickly, some things
that we need to cover off.
Short-form content needs very,
very good hooks.
In long-form content, so short-form,
good hooks.
Long-form, we can jump to the setup.
And the reason I say that
is the packaging on a YouTube video
is almost the
hook.
What wins in a fight between a bodybuilder
and 10 midgets?
I'm clicking on that video,
but once I've clicked it,
I can go straight
into the setup.
There's a common belief
that midgets can't fight, and in this
video, we're going to expose whether
or not one bodybuilder... See what I mean?
So you could think
that the packaging for a YouTube video
is the hook.
Okay.
Should you be coming up with the hooks?
Yes.
And the best way
that you should come up with the hook
is this: how can I make
people interested in this video in three
seconds? That's it. Hooks take time.
Things take time. This
is a skill you want to
develop. If I gave you a yo-yo,
and you've never used a yo-yo before,
if you
used a yo-yo every day for three minutes,
within a year, you'd be quite good at
yo-yoing. You know what I mean?
Okay.
Now we're just going to quickly look at
the setup, then we're going to get
into some questions. So as far as setup,
at home,
you can just face natural light with a
blank wall behind you.
Any of you that followed me for a while,
I built my following to over a million
followers recording on my bedroom floor on
a tripod. Now, in this setup,
I'll be real with you, we've
got a key light here. This
is a main big box light, which is nice.
This creates a dark side on this side,
which is called Rembrandt, as an effect.
If we move that more to the side,
it gives more of a dramatic look.
We're then using something called a hair
light on this side.
So you see this nice little bit of shine
on my face?
That's coming from the hair light.
Another thing to consider
is rule of thirds.
If you were to grid up this screen like
you do on iPhone, you'll notice that
my eye line is on the top third.
What we don't want,
and I made a mistake recording
some reels this week,
we don't want to be in the middle of a
screen.
So if you are on mobile,
you want your eyes on the top third,
not the
middle. Captions,
probably just below the chin,
because we do want the eyes
to go from the captions to the eye line.
When it comes to audio,
I actually have a directional mic out of
shot just
here. Audio is crucial.
I would say you can have an average
picture, but you cannot
have average audio.
When it comes to cameras,
go to a secondhand camera store. This
is probably my best bit of advice
because you can get a brand-new,
really good camera,
but for the same money,
you can get a secondhand,
much better camera where they're going to
give you a
better guarantee the lens
is going to be sick
and the camera's going to be sick.
And for most of us,
we're filming for fucking nine minutes a
day.
We don't need the most expensive shit.
I am using an ND filter here, which
is like sunglasses for the lens, but I
can't stress this enough.
The majority of you watching this do not
need to care about this
yet. When you get the resources
and you get the income, sure.
We did quarter of a million dollars in a
month, and I was like, "Do you know what?
I should probably build a studio." I
should probably build a studio because
doing
a quarter of a million dollars in a month
from my own business and not having a
studio just started getting a bit silly,
and we built aircon and whatnot.
Now, for this live stream, this
is something...
Because what you're actually seeing
is my strategy in real time.
All the things I'm teaching you,
I'm actually learning at the same time.
So someone said to me, "Oh,
how's Score App going?" I was like,
"I'll let you know
in a few months."
But the last webinar we did
crushed. From real-time sales, good,
but then also just the follow-up
sequences.
So any of you that buy today,
you'll get to go through all of the
sequences, you get the offer, everything,
et
cetera.
But there could be even a model where I
make these a
monthly thing just because they work
really well for the business.
Now, for the live stream,
one thing you're probably noticing
is I look pretty good.
Thanks.
So I'm using a wired connection for a
start.
For any of you that
are going to do a live stream,
just wire a connection.
I'm using a 20-meter Ethernet cable
that goes all the way downstairs into the
router. Second thing,
I'm using a Cam Link 4K, which allows my
camera to send a high signal into the
laptop.
And there's a platform at the moment I'm
using called Meld, M-E-L-D, which is
the best one that I've used so far for
streaming because it's idiot-proof.
So there's some of the things
that you need there,
but for the majority of you, you
just need your preview on QuickTime,
so you can plug in your phone with your
USB-C,
and you just need a tripod
and a good microphone.
Now, DJI
probably do the best mics.
The Hollyland ones are pretty good,
bit cheaper, but I'd
say DJI is the king.
Okay.
So we're now going to move into some more
questions,
and I anticipate
that one of them will be about stealing
content from other people.
But let's see if that's something that's
on your radar.
Hope you're enjoying this.
Some people are like, "Oh, like
and please subscribe."
Don't care.
How is having an avatar
and speaking to Susan different from a
niche? Okay.
So when I speak to Susan,
Susan Green,
some people will come that aren't Susan,
and that's great.
So I put a video out speaking to Susan,
and Dave, a 43-year-old
bricklayer, comes along. "You all right,
mate?
Seen your videos online,
seem like a no-nonsense guy.
How do I get started?"
If I niche, "Hey, if you're a 45-year-old
woman who's not in work because you're
rich and you drive a white
Porsche Cayenne GTS,
come into the gym." So if I niche,
I'm excluding huge amounts of people,
whereas if I speak to an audience here,
I'm
not. So for instance, Brian Mark
is the business
coach for personal trainers.
I'm not. Now,
even though I'm talking to my perfect
client right now,
what if I used the example, wills
and probate lawyer, accountant, exercise
physiologist, personal trainer.
Someone comes along and goes,
"I'm a carpenter.
I'm joining." Cool.
But if I niche,
I'm picking a small part of the market,
and I want to go wider than
personal trainers. So a niche
is where you're segmenting out loads of
people,
and avatar is where you're talking to one
demographic with hope that other people
come in.
So that's how I differentiate them.
The Longevity Coach.
I've started my Insta three months ago,
grown to 12K.
Should my focus be squeezing for emails
before any kind of selling, then purely
sell through emails? No.
So my golden rule is 20% of your audience
should be on
your email list.
20% of your audience on the email list.
So right now, at 12K, what should that be?
1,200, 2,400.
Your email list should be 2,400.
If it's not, you fucked up.
[chuckles]
If it's not at 2,400, even
if it's at 1,000, you're still
so far behind that I would put all of your
focus into growing your email list.
So there's two marketing rules here
that I've got.
If you're full, you're too cheap.
There's no way you can argue
that to me in any
realm, and if you're not full,
you're not marketing hard enough.
Push that to the side. The other side is,
if 20% of your following
is on your email list,
you need to grow your socials, and
if it's not, you need to
grow your email list. So
right now,
you should have all those people on there.
Now,
you're at 12,000 followers in three
months. That's great.
How are you selling to people
if not emails?
Because I've been to some of the world's
best steak restaurants, and they do not
let you in based on the amount of likes
that you get on your Instagram posts.
So yeah,
I would then only sell through emails.
And we're going to get onto this in kind
of the next section, but yeah.
You'll notice that even now,
I'm not selling to you guys on here.
I did a talk in Sydney a few weeks ago,
and
that Brian Mark guy I was talking about,
his talk was 45 minutes,
but his sales pitch was 15 of that.
So I was asked to do a
45-minute talk.
I gave 45 minutes of value and said,
"If you want to
join my program,
cool." He gave a 30-minute talk,
then sold for 15 minutes,
and it was just a bit fucking pathetic,
if I'm honest.
So I don't really like selling.
Even in this,
I'm going to say to you there's a
link in the description.
I'm going to follow up with an email.
But why the fuck would I waste your time
right now trying to make myself
sound amazing? "Oh, hey, guys.
Just to take a short break from this
webinar,
here's Sally. She joined three months ago.
Look at the results she got." Fuck that.
So that's why.
I think your social media should be
reserved for making
awesome fucking content to people in the
longevity space.
Then the email should be for people
that go, "Go on." And you could get some
clients from that. Although,
I'm not going to lie to you,
this longevity
stuff, to me, it's a bit...
Brian Johnson, who could be your
sensei, I'm not sure,
he's what? Like 48 or whatever.
We're not going to know
if his longevity stuff works for decades.
If he dies at fucking 60.
He's done everything.
It's actually a genius thing to do.
"Hi, my name's James Smith,
and I'm going to live to 250 years old.
Buy my supplements now." Then
if I pop it at 60,
I've already got all the money.
I've already spent it all. So yeah.
Andrea.
Hello, James.
I'm launching a fitness app next week.
Don't do it.
Do you have any tips for marketing it?
Most fitness apps
are garbage they're marketing too. No,
I'm only joking.
Yes
Email list.
I would say have coverage of tenfold.
So if you want 1,000 people on your
coaching app,
get 10,000 on the email list,
because one in 10 people will actually
probably do it.
So if you're launching the app next week,
I do hope that's kind of the place that
you've gone with it,
because to sell a fitness app, you need to
sell the story a bit.
So you need in your email, "Two years ago,
we discovered this problem.
For this reason,
we had to build this as a solution.
I'm proud to announce it's out next week,"
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. So yeah.
Be interested to know how many
are on your email list.
Okay.
With regards to hooks, when people
are doom scrolling and the phone volume
is down,
how do you create a great hook that's both
audible and visual?
Okay,
most people doom scroll with the volume
on,
but all of you should have captions. Now,
there's a caveat to this.
I fucking hate it
when people put a block of
text
and captions and start a video,
because we cannot read two things at the
same
time.
So if you go with a big exasperated
visual, like
putting something on a table
or picking something up,
people can just read the hook
anyway. Most people
are watching fucking Prime Video with
subtitles on anyway. So
if the audio's down, have captions.
They can use the captions.
But I would say not many people doom
scroll without
volume,
unless they're in a doctor's waiting room
or something.
In that case, just use the captions.
Then most people just do, I think,
where they scroll up, scroll down,
they get the
hook again.
"I've been posting on Instagram daily for
the past three months.
I'm still struggling to grow my followers
and generate leads.
Do you have any tips?" Yes.
Post better. Because every video
that you make,
Instagram wants to put in front of 50
million people, but the reason it can't is
it's not good enough.
If any of you have got issues like this,
give me your Instagram handle and let's
have a little look. So Gia Fruco, get
your social media handle out.
Dan Devonside, good to see you again.
"Would it be a good idea to master
short-form content before moving on to
YouTube,
or do you advise going straight into it?"
Yeah, because you need to eat shit on
short-form for a very long time. Also,
you need to become pretty good at
speaking,
cadence, editing, lighting, setup,
ideation, all the skills you develop in
short-form. Think of it this way.
If you want to crush as an online
coach, you need to do in-person. Now,
in-person sucks in
many ways. Many ways. Long hours,
no-shows,
clients, on your feet.
But the more you're willing to suck on the
floor and eat shit,
the better you'll be online.
It's the exact same.
So short-form content,
you're going to get a million views on a
video and your
bank account's barely going to nudge.
But the more you can eat shit,
doing, "Oh, whoa, whoa,
whoa," people spamming your fucking
Instagrams.
Not like that. I didn't mean like that.
I meant, if you've got a question,
ask the question, then
put your handle at the end,
so I don't have to come back to it.
So you can stop that. Dan Devonside.
So the longer you spend in-person on the
gym floor, the better you'll be online
because you've got more experience.
The more you spend on short-form
dominating,
the easier it will be to go online.
There's also another caveat to that,
that if your face becomes familiar,
when you
go online,
people will recognize your face.
So that's one thing.
Jackal Gind.
"Trial reels on Instagram.
Should they be the same as main?
Worth spamming meme content or useless?
Getting views on them,
but not many followers." You've kind of
answered your own
question. The trial reels, I think,
is a tool,
twofold, for creators to try new things.
Because let's say we want to try something
new.
Most creators are petrified that
if they try something new,
everyone's just going
to leave and abandon.
So it's a good idea to trial something.
What it isn't,
is a gamification for you to get free
followers and to beat the
algorithm.
So I think a lot of people do seem to
think the trial reels is like
some fucking magical hack. It's not.
And the thing is, some people are like,
"Yeah, but I've used
trials reels and I've grown 10,000
followers." I'm like, yeah, but
if you just
reposted all your old fucking videos to
your whole audience, you probably would've
got 10,000 followers. The fact is,
for trial reels, it permitted
people to triple the amount they
were posting.
And lo and behold,
they got better results.
So yes,
I'm sure for some people it's quite good,
but if you just try and abuse it, I'm
pretty sure they take your function away.
But the other standpoint would be,
if you want to double your amount of
posting
frequency, just post old shit again.
I've been doing it recently
and getting six-figure views on
everything.
So it's one of those things.
It's one of those things. I would say
it's not the be all and end all.
You could get the same results without
trial
reels. David Cooper, "What do you do
if you work full-time
and at this point you don't have anything
to sell as of yet?
I have 24,000 followers now from free
value.
How would you collect emails?" We're going
to get onto that in a second,
but if you work full-time,
think of it this way.
You need to very quickly decide this.
How much business do I need to be better
off?
The longer you leave this,
the more you get paid in full-time work.
But if you need 60 clients to be better
off
and you think you can have a better life
being self-employed, you need to make the
jump.
But you remaining in this safe employed
life
is like a prison that's going to kill your
dreams and ambitions, and the longer you
stay in that prison,
the more fucked you are.
So luckily for me,
when I went from in-person to online,
I was making
all right money, but my prison wasn't
that big.
But if I was in a corporate job paying 60,
70K a year, it would've made that jump a
lot more difficult. Now,
the only analogy I have for you is this.
Imagine wanting to be a premiership rugby
side, but you wanted
all your rugby players to still have a
job. You're going to get spanked.
You're going to get fucked by Harlequins.
Northampton Saints
are going to run amok with you.
Do you know why?
Because all day every day,
they're just focusing on rugby,
whilst you're
going to your accountancy job
or working in the city.
Semi-pro will never beat professional.
Fuck, you won't even beat me. Because
if you're having to go
to a job all the other time, your mind
is in a different place, and it's going to
be incredibly difficult.
If you want to leave your job
and you want to really
fucking go at this,
you're going to need to.
But yeah, you've done the hard part.
You've got 24,000 followers.
The only concern here
is there's no guarantee
that that's going to
equate to clients. So let me explain this.
My big YouTube channel, that one
Got like half a million YouTube subs,
and I went to sell Nutonic on it
and it didn't really work that well.
And it's because I cultivated an audience
just for the sake of cultivating an
audience. So, what I mean by that is,
just because I had followers there
doesn't mean that I'm going to get
business from it because I just kind of
created
a vanity audience.
Whereas this channel has only got 50,000
subs,
but it's generated me nearly $4.5 million
in the last two years. So,
[sighs]
I hope to God those 24,000
are enough for you to leave your job,
but we just
don't know.
Dude Lucas, "Polarizing opinions
and rage bait content.
Thoughts on this?" Polarizing opinions,
yes. Rage bait, no.
Polarizing opinions
is great because some people will agree
with you,
but rage bait,
very rarely you're going to get a client
from it.
Polarizing opinions, you might say...
A lot of the things I say are polarizing.
I did a video this morning saying
that the majority of personal trainers eat
a lot
of shit in their diet.
Some personal trainers
are going to be like, "Oh, what'd you
say?" But
I'm not going to do rage bait content
where I start a video going,
"Bench press is
the best back exercise going." You know
what I mean?
So.
Third Nutonic of the day. That's huge.
"Is education and value-based content
really worthwhile?
I struggle to get any traction with that.
I can't show my work all the time due to
launch timelines."
Okay. Is education
and value-based content really worthwhile?
Have you ever seen a TED Talk?
Because there's a channel on YouTube with
tens of millions of
subscribers and tens of millions of views,
and all it is is an idea
worth sharing that changes someone's
perspective. And people love it.
And [chuckles] let's have a look at this.
I'm glad you gave your Insta handle here.
Let's have a little look,
because it's a good question.
PreFlight Creative.
Let's have a look.
Building brands and packaging with
purpose, personality, and profit baked in.
Okay.
You're an FMCG design specialist. Okay,
first thing, I'm going to...
Let me see if this works. Probably not.
So I'm on yours now.
You've done 170 posts,
for a start, which just is not a lot.
Okay? It's just not a lot.
It's not a lot at all. So is education
and value-based content really worthwhile?
You've done 170 posts, which is nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
Sorry that that didn't work
when I showed it that before.
There's no personal brand
here. So you're called PreFlight, cool,
but it looks to
me like you're a lovely young lady,
which your name could be Sora or Sariah.
Sariah, is it?
So the reason that I don't think this
account is working
is you're trying to be a
company. Now,
people on Instagram very rarely follow
companies.
They like to follow people. For instance,
you don't follow Modern Wisdom, you
follow Chris Williamson.
You don't follow Diary of a CEO,
you follow Steven
Bartlett.
You don't follow acquisition.com,
you follow Alex Hormozi.
So that's why all my channels
are called James Smith.
Because you like to follow James Smith.
So for first,
I've got no inclination to follow a
business, but if you're
a person, I like the person, 100%.
Now, second thing is,
if I click onto your reels,
you're not in them.
Who am I watching again here?
This is just a bit of text.
Oh, there you go. There you are.
You're there.
Oh,
I don't like these thumbnails because
when I go through your profile, I look
like I'm just looking at memes,
not necessarily anything.
Now,
I would say you haven't found your voice.
You haven't really
quite cracked it. But 170 posts,
723 followers, you're not doing
bad. I would change this
to just be you. Put your name here,
and instead of having PreFlight Business,
FMCG Design Specialist,
just have Sariah, if that's your name.
I help people build brands in the
packaging space. Boom.
Connects here. So I would say this
is pretty much what a
very early-stage page looks like.
The reason I say this
is my PT page used to be called James
Smith Training,
and it wasn't a picture of me, it
was some fucking stupid logo.
So yeah.
You need to keep doing education
and value-based content because that's how
you're
going to win people over for clients.
Every single one of my videos has some
inclination towards a lesson that
people can learn.
Because people learn from you enough
and they get to a point
where they go, "Fuck it,
let's work together."
Thomas,
"I posted daily for about a year
and better value content for about five
months. I'm at 370 followers,
but growth is just super slow.
Retention graph just shows it's a hook
issue, but I don't know." I don't really
like the retention graphs on Instagram
because people aren't choosing to click
on your content. Does that make sense?
I would look at content on
YouTube because people decided to watch
it,
but let's have a look.
Tom Woodham, all with a full stop.
A physiotherapist personal trainer.
Here we go. 370 followers.
Physiotherapist.
422 posts.
You're trying to do the sit-down thing in
content.
I think you've got, again,
for anyone out there, Tom Woodham dot,
I think
you've probably just got to find your
voice a bit more on this.
I tell you what,
I'm going to add you to my next YouTube
video that I do on this.
You're getting there,
but your video's content, what's better,
squats versus leg extension for
longevity?
I don't think people really care about
that too much.
[sighs]
I'm not sold on that one.
I think you probably just have to go
through the reps
again, better at content.
So two case studies for you here.
We've got a lady in the mentorship called
Olivia.
She was at 1,300 posts,
5,000 followers. By 1,800 posts,
she's got 200,000.
Same as Craig Jackson.
I think Craig Jackson
was at 1,500 posts before he blew up.
So, a lot of the time, and this
is going to sound really shitty to say,
a lot of
the time when you're creating content,
you
might have to create a thousand posts
before things kick off.
And that's not the algorithm,
it's not your account, it's you.
At 500 posts,
you just might not have had enough
feedback to really
understand where you're going wrong yet.
You probably need a bit more lighting for
your setup.
But yeah. Jamie Runstrong,
"You talked about previously going live
earlier in your career.
Do you strictly Q&As,
or did you have a structure
pre-planned?" Let me tell you this, bro.
Nothing I do is that well-planned,
I'll tell you that.
So for the Q&As,
because I had no one following me,
I just made up the first three
questions. I just made them up.
I just literally got to the point
where I was like,
"I'm going to make up three questions I
know the answers to,"
so that when I
start doing the live,
I will sound like I know what I'm on
about.
But yeah, ultimately,
I don't really structure them that much.
Just go live,
have some things to talk about,
have some things ready in your
pocket, in your armory.
So, yeah.
Wait, Andre, stop spamming,
you prick,
or I'll block you,
and you won't be able to watch anything.
Jonathan, last question, "What
are your thoughts on paid ads for
followers to your
Instagram account? Currently post daily,
don't gain many followers, though paid
ads, I gain 20 a day.
Thoughts?" All right.
This is going to sound harsh,
but I'm just going to throw it out there.
Paid ads for followers, why?
You're spending money for a fucking
follower.
That's a vanity metric that's not going to
pay bills.
Now, your problem here is
that you post daily
and don't get many followers from it.
That is a signal, not that, "Oh,
get your wallet out." That's a
signal that your content
is not doing what it needs to do.
You need to master organic as a golden
rule before you do paid.
I'm sorry, but you do. Because even
when it comes to paid ads, if you're
shit at organic content
and you're just throwing money at it,
fine.
But me doing years and years
and years of organic content,
we still haven't nailed
ads for fucking my coaching app.
It's eight years old.
You need to become good at organic because
when you put money on top of something as
a catalyst, the origin still has to be
good. So yeah, paid ads, 20 a day.
I would say if it's not working organic,
it's not working.
Actually, if anything,
I would say only put paid on posts
that are really doing
well anyway, not ones that aren't.
Because if you're having to
put money on a post
that won't even move organically,
it's like trying to thumb in
a floppy cock.
Probably best to take a step back
and address the
situation. So, not mad on that. Now,
if you were to say you're putting money
on a post and it's getting you emails,
then I could get on board with that.
But unfortunately, not anything else.
Okay,
so we're going to move into the next
section of this.
Hopefully, you guys are enjoying this.
Again,
there is going to be a link for an offer
in the description and the
comments. If you want to join, cool.
If not, also cool.
Probably going to have to close up shop a
little bit in January, February, whilst I
rebuild Mentorship 3.0, so
whatever. Okay, next thing.
The next element that we've gone from
social is we're now going to squeeze. Now,
squeeze is a lead magnet.
Squeeze is where you squeeze your audience
for their data.
So this webinar, let's think about it.
I went to socials with organic and paid,
squeezed you guys for your email address,
got your email address.
We're now doing this webinar as a
deliverability.
Now,
some of you thinking about lead magnets,
you're like, "What could I do?
Should I build an e-book?
Should I build a free course?" Yeah, or
do a fucking webinar. Because for this,
the effort comes after the lead magnet,
if that makes sense.
So rather than spending a month building
something and then getting data from it, I
was like,
"I'm going to get all these email
addresses." How many did I get?
3,101. So I got 3,101 email addresses, of
which 500 are currently watching at the
moment, which is fine.
The other 2,500 people get an email hit.
They're probably in different time zones
or whatever it is.
So, I come up with a campaign.
I'm going to do a webinar.
What am I going to do the webinar on?
Reverse engineer it from a problem.
How am I going to deliver it?
Live stream on YouTube.
How are we going to get people to attend?
We're going to get their email addresses.
What about the people that don't attend?
We're going to send them a fucking offer
anyway.
I did a webinar maybe a year ago
where I wasn't using Meld,
the streaming platform,
and it dropped out after 17
minutes. Whole stream was gone,
lost everyone.
But because I had everyone's email
address, I emailed everyone, "Hey, sorry,
the
webinar dropped out. I'll fix it my end.
Here's an offer,
ten grand." Did ten grand straight away,
Bosch.
So,
if you have someone's email address first,
things can go
catastrophically wrong,
and you'll still be fine.
That's why email is king,
because you just have the ability to tap
someone up and
just let them know, "Hey, I'm doing this.
Hey, I'm doing this.
Hey, here's an offer.
Hey." Nutonic currently on TikTok Shop.
Head there now.
Don't go on TikTok Shop,
head to the website.
It's where you're going to get the best
offers.
Now,
I'm sure the majority of the questions
that come from this
will come through shortly.
But the main thing about email marketing,
and any email marketing
questions, get them in now.
The main thing is this.
I like to segment emails into two things,
automations, broadcasts.
So automations, over Christmas,
I pre-wrote 15 emails, let's
say.
I then send them to get categorized and
automated. They go out, boom, boom, boom,
boom, boom.
There are also sequences that I have,
so when people join a certain email list,
there's an automation.
Send email,
send email, send email, send email.
And when you set these up in the back end,
it will look like, send email one, wait
24 hours. Send email two, wait 24 hours.
Send email three, et cetera.
Now, broadcasts are when I just sit down.
So today, at some point,
I'm going to open my laptop,
open up SendGrid,
my email marketing account.
I'm going to choose my list with 500,000
people on, and I'm just going to chat shit
about today.
I might talk about Venezuela
and fucking Trump.
I might talk about anything I want to.
A broadcast is something you do with
something relative that's happened to your
life. It could be something good,
could be something bad,
could be a Facebook
memory, could be on this day last year.
Because stories are really,
really big Important and powerful.
Stories predate money.
Stories predate everything.
Like, how do you get people to go to war?
You tell them a convincing story.
How do you get people to pray five times a
day?
You give them a convincing story.
How do you get people to all of these
things,
right?
Humans love stories.
It's what religions
are at the end of the day.
So instead of just doing an email,
four ways to lose fat.
Tell a story.
Go back into your Facebook mems,
find a picture.
This is me six years ago, hook and story.
Then every good story has some kind of
challenge that the person has to
face. So
this is me six years ago,
drinking too much, snorting too much coke,
hanging the
back out of anything above a three out of
10.
What happened? This was the challenge.
This is how I overcame it.
This is how you can relate to it.
Here's the solution. Buy now.
True story. So with all of those things,
a broadcast is an opportunity for a story,
and automation is an
opportunity to really pepper people.
And how that could look
is you could get someone sign up to your
email
list. Email one,
here's a free trial to my app.
Email two, did you request a program?
Email three,
we have a money-back guarantee.
Email four, these
are what our customers say about us.
Email five, here's a membership offer
that will be perfect for you.
Email six, if you're not interested,
try this.
And in automations,
you can also segment it so that,
say you pepper
someone for 21 days
and they don't buy your product,
you can then wait four
days and hit them with a lower offer.
So for instance,
if you don't buy my mentorship,
you get hit for short-form content
masteries,
then we might as well get your advertising
spend back.
So as far as email marketing, that
is pretty much the
crux of it,
but your questions will probably help me a
lot with
this.
So Yellow Brick Road,
how would you email market if you were a
tradie,
and how would you gain the email
addresses?
So for this, it would be about what trade,
what are you doing?
What problems do you solve?
So
what I would do for something,
let's say you're a tradie and you do
electric gates, let's say.
You could put out a lead magnet,
like the lead magnet could be a quote.
How much would electric gates cost to your
property?
Click this button
and we'll do a free AI analysis,
where they send a
picture [chuckles] of their electric gates
in their home.
You could say it's AI,
but you could actually just have a
salesperson that then
mocks up an image, sends it back,
and calls them up on the phone.
Something like that.
Use our free AI app that quotes
within one day how much electric gates
would cost at your house.
So you go there,
you take a picture of their house,
they upload it into the lead
magnet. One of your sales team gets it.
Because think about that,
out of all the inquiries,
how hard would it be to close
someone?
And you could be running paid ads for a
small segment of the market.
Here's one for you.
So I've just had an outdoor shower built
in my house.
And,
so the outdoor shower,
I've wanted one for ages because we live
opposite the beach,
and I called so many people.
They just don't want the fucking business.
Tradies just don't want the fucking
business.
So in the end, I end up messaging Tay.
I said,
"Who do you know who would know someone
who does showers?" So I got a
contact to this guy. He comes out,
and he goes,
"Do you want hot water?" I was
like, "Nah, I don't care." And he goes,
"Trust me, mate,
you want hot water." I go,
"Go on then." So him
and this other guy come out.
They fit this railway sleeper.
They're just amazing.
Copper shower outside my house.
I'm showering outside all the time now.
I'm having hot showers outside my house.
It feels ridiculous doing it in the house.
Even now I'm like, "Why
are we getting the bathroom floor wet?
I'm going to shower outside." Anyway,
so my neighbors then see it,
and I'm saying to my neighbors, "Oi,
when you're coming back, use my shower."
Because I love my shower so much,
I want other people to use it.
I've told all my neighbors, "Hey,
come help yourself to a hot shower." So my
neighbors then say, "How much was it?"
And I told them the truth. "I don't know.
I haven't had the invoice yet." Because I
wanted the shower so bad, I didn't care.
So then they said, "Well,
you let me know how much it costs." I go,
"Cool."
So then I send them the invoice
when it comes. They go, "That's great.
We're going to get one too." So my
marketing brain goes like this.
Hold on. You wanted something,
but not enough to inquire for it.
You wanted something,
but not enough to inquire.
When you saw mine, the only thing
that stopped you from buying it was the
price.
So I went to the guy
that installed the shower.
I said, "Come back round, take pictures.
You're going to do a carousel post." He
did a carousel post.
Picture one,
how much does one of these showers cost to
make?
Slide two, how much was the sleeper,
the concreting, the labor, the stones, the
copper pipes, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba.
Then the last one reveals the price.
So his hook was the question
that people would have had.
If my neighbors had seen that post,
they would've got the payoff
that they needed
to book their own. So even as a tradie,
you could say to someone,
the free quote would be a good one.
Saying, "What is it you want?
Put it into this box." Run a paid ad.
Then the second they do that,
they get an email back straight away.
"Hey,
we're actually available on the 3rd of
fucking February.
Can we come out?" Blah, blah, blah.
Give us your mobile number,
whatever it is.
So it definitely depends on what you're
doing.
But for me, to that guy, I said to him,
"How many showers and bathrooms have you
fitted? And why is it only now
that you're revealing the price?" Say you
do someone's bathroom,
and you do an amazing job.
Why not turn that into a carousel?
Turn it into a story.
Here's the before, here's the after.
Here's the things we did.
This is how much it costs.
Because for so many people,
the amount it costs is the
very barrier they're waiting for before
they book.
So the shower was like four grand Aussie
dollars, which I thought was good.
My neighbor's like, "That's great.
I'll book one in." So he's never shown
pricing on his socials before, but I've
given him the evidence that that
is the very thing
that he should be showing,
because people just don't want to get
bummed.
They don't want to waste your time.
So any coaches out there, right,
those of you that don't hide pricing,
you think
it's good for your business,
but you're leaving so many leads on the
table because
so many people will want to... Me,
I don't care.
Me, I don't give a fuck about the price.
My neighbors did,
and they would only book
and get a shower if they knew the price
first.
So where you might get clients like me,
you wouldn't get clients like them.
Okay.
Sanna,
"What do you think of LinkedIn as a
channel?" I'm still figuring it out.
I'm going to spend two years figuring it
out.
It's getting some sales at the moment,
get some traction. It's all right.
I repurposed my marketing emails there.
Same with the podcast.
If you were to say to me,
"How's the podcast going?" I'd go,
"Ask me in two years."
Because I've learnt a lot in my career,
and it's this,
you can't judge something till you've
given it your all for two years.
It's pretty much truth. Some of you
are like, "Oh, I've done 400 posts
on Instagram." I'm like,
"I've done more than
that on LinkedIn this year or last
year." So,
you need to really commit to things for it
to take off. Same as jujitsu, right?
No one really loves jujitsu till they've
got their blue belt two years in, but you
just got to stick with it. Super Psy,
"With regards to email marketing, you
mentioned about creating a campaign.
What are good campaigns to run in order to
get them?
Additionally,
how do you structure your talks?" Right,
that's two questions.
Let's do the first.
"You mentioned about creating a campaign.
What's a good campaign to run in order to
get them?" Okay, so you might
need emails for a certain outcome. So,
is it emails for a webinar?
This is how it works in my mind.
Working with clients
is the gold star. Do you know what?
I'm going to be honest with you.
I don't need to work with the people in my
mentorship. I don't.
At this stage,
I've got such good coaches in there,
I could easily
wash my hands, hire three more people,
and back out like Homer Simpson going into
a
bush.
But there's two reasons I'm in the
mentorship.
One, yes, help people, yes,
help them make more money, yes,
scale their businesses,
yes, change their lives. But ultimately,
two, for ideas.
That's the main reason I'm in there.
Because when I help people
and work with them, they
are feeding me all of
these things, and I'll spot trends.
So one week,
they'll just be fucking inundations of
people
wanting their landing page looked at.
And then I'll notice it's the same seven
issues that everyone has.
So I go, "Hmm, if people
that have paid me thousands of dollars
are having this
problem,
there are probably hundreds of people
that could pay me thousands of
dollars to have that problem." And there,
a lead magnet is born.
Ah. The highly converted landing page.
Put it together, boom,
11-email automation after, job done,
great. Another thing,
when I created the mentorship,
it didn't have
short-form content mastery.
But then the content thread, boom, boom,
boom, boom,
was just going off.
So then a lead magnet was born. Ah.
But instead, the lead magnet
was a $99 course.
And you might think,
"Why do $99?" Because some people would
rather pay $99 than
get something for free. Then
this very question you're having now,
what's a good lead magnet? Ah.
Created a lead magnet course called Lead
Magnet Mastery.
So every time I stumble across a common
theme or I spot a trend with my audience,
I then take that, package it,
create it as a free lead magnet
or a paid program within the existing
ecosystem. That's what I would say.
Because you've got to watch the landscape,
and you've got to monitor where these
trends are coming from.
Okay. Saar, "I have 2,000 or so emails,
but I think quite a few are simply not
engaged.
I'm trying to reengage by asking to click
to stay on or subscribe.
The majority do neither.
Any ideas for motivation?" That's not your
job,
bro.
Your job is to get them to click through
to the offer and buy.
And anyone that doesn't do
that can fuck off.
It's not about engagement,
it's about sales.
Asking them to click or stay on
or unsubscribe, no.
If they don't click your offer, fuck them.
And do you know what?
If they don't open the emails,
kick them off the fucking list.
And if you've got 2,000 on an email list
that aren't doing anything,
fuck them all off and start fresh.
You're not there as a motivation page,
mate.
You're there to get sales.
And people should be working their way in
and out the
funnels.
There's no point going on Hinge
and getting 10 matches and doing nothing
with it. I'd rather go on Hinge,
which I can't as a taken man.
I'd rather get eight noes
and two yeses than fucking have 10 people
there waiting
to organize a date.
So start spamming that list. And again,
if I ask you to shrink that list
from 2,000 to 500,
you might get a couple fucking clients out
of it.
Aaron Kirkby,
"How would you build an email list as a
videographer who creates content
and helps people grow their business via
content
and paid ads?"
Well, okay. Right.
How would you build an email list?
You're a videographer who creates content
and help people grow their business via
content. Cool. So you should have big
social followings on how to edit,
how to create content, how to film,
how to do
lighting, exposure, f-stop,
all of these things, right?
Then each one of those videos should
probably have a lead magnet in it,
where it
teaches people how to assign colors
and LUTs and exposure, and
how they can color grade
and all those things, right?
Then on the back of that,
you should have email marketing
automation set up,
so once they've done the free course,
they then get
access to your paid program
or mentorship or whatever,
where you can get them a
tangible return on investment, right?
Because if you haven't got those things
set up,
it's mental. Declan, my videographer,
from editing my videos, has
now grown a YouTube channel where he
teaches people how to color grade and then
sells a LUT off the back of it.
And he does that because it worked for
other people.
And
I'm just going to throw this out there.
If you teach people how to grow their
business via content,
why are you asking me how to build an
email list?
Because if you get paid to teach people to
grow their business,
how do you not already know this?
Just going to throw that out there.
Again, I could be completely wrong, but I
would have an issue
if you're taking people's money to teach
them how to
build a business,
and you don't know how to build an email
list.
That would be a bit of a red flag.
But I could be completely misconstruing
that. True Fit Online. Straight away,
get rid of that.
True Fit. True Fit.
I've seen so many True Fits.
Were you the True Fit
that came to the Sydney event wearing the
T-shirt?
Unless you own the True Fit copy mark,
just stop it. Just stop it.
"What email marketing platform do you use
at the moment? I have AWeber set up.
I can't get on with it." Mate, AWeber
is the simplest one. It's the best one.
I use AWeber. I love it.
How can you not get on with it?
I don't know.
If you think that AWeber's hard,
go to fucking Klaviyo.
Steppy,
"I've been messing around with trying to
set up a quiz of sorts to get
emails, but my biggest problem
is the cost of the different softwares.
Any recommendations to keep costs down?"
If you're worried about keeping
costs down, then don't use it
Ultimately, because
if you're trying to find a cheap quiz
software,
it's going to be shit.
So
for me to build out my latest quiz cost me
$10,000 US, and that's with
ScoreApp. And I said to them, "Yeah,
have 10 grand, because this is worth
way more to me than 10 grand." But
if you want to do it cheap, do it
cheap. What you shouldn't do is try
and do an expensive method cheap.
If you just want to get emails,
just use a fucking lead magnet, mate.
If you want to do it for free,
have the payoff of what they're getting in
the lead
magnet in the automations. So I have
that 30 Ways in 30 Days to Improve Your
Business lead magnet.
I might be able to even put it here.
[keyboard clicking] There you go.
I posted it so you can have a look later
on.
But that 30-day lead magnet
is easy because all I had to do was
deliver what I promised in the lead
magnet.
Early Bird Fitness.
Is it good to have a personal page with
name and then separate
coaching page for brand to post more of a
range of stuff on personal, more serious?
[lip smack] Not really.
I built the James Smith Academy page.
It's got nearly 100,000
followers,
but I still think the majority of them
come through the James Smith
page. If I could go back,
I don't know if I'd have it.
A lot of the big brands like Sweat have
got Sweatup,
but
for me,
a lot of the time it's just a bit of a
distraction.
And you know when coaches collab their
stuff with their training page?
It just looks a bit cringe.
I know I'm doing it this week,
but it looks a bit
cringe.
I
know Adam Sullivan does it, but [sighs]
the only caveat to
that would be my brand morphization
concept,
where if you know you're going to get out
of fitness, potentially, because
Adam's got evidence-based training,
and his Cunny's Gummies might be more on
his Adam Solo.
For me, I might do more Nutonic on that,
but the only thing is,
just don't expect your training page to
have some crazy
engagement and results.
A lot of the time it can be a distraction.
Let me tell you this.
I run three or four Instagram
accounts, and I run three
or four businesses.
Oh,
do I miss the days of just having one
Instagram and one business.
The simpler it is, the easier.
You could just put all your focus in one
place.
So don't create different accounts to do
different things, to be in different
places at different times,
because ultimately it's just a bit
exhausting, if I'm honest.
Okay,
so we're going to move into the next
section.
Don't worry people, not much longer.
You've got to listen to me for maybe
another half hour. All right?
[chuckles]
But this stuff's good, and
if you learn this stuff,
you're going to do very well.
So we've gone through socials,
we've gone through squeeze.
The pages that you can squeeze from
are going to be hosted on email marketing
platforms. We've got AWeber, Klaviyo,
MailerLite, Mailchimp.
Don't like Mailchimp.
All of these different places you can go
to.
So now we're getting onto the stage of
having a landing page. Now, this is sell.
Socials,
squeeze,
sell. Selling is probably the thing
that I'm best at.
So you want to create a page
that you send people to where some people
buy.
It's like a menu. It's like
if you were to open a Vietnamese
restaurant in your local town,
90% of the work is getting someone to go
on it from Deliveroo or Uber Eats.
Once they're on that page
and they can see the photos
and see the pho and see the
prices, that's it.
The hardest part for that restaurant
is just getting seen.
So we need a page, like a menu,
to just tell people what it is that we're
selling them and why they need it.
And it sounds overly simple, but that's
fucking it.
The amount of people I speak to,
"Do you have a landing page?" "No."
That's fucking stupid. "Oh yeah,
but my offer is very complex." Then
fucking tear it up, mate.
So many people will need to see a landing
page before
they buy. A good example of this,
I hired a dog trainer, and he was shit.
He came round to the house,
fed my dog fucking treats,
and got him to sit on the
balcony. Cool.
Next dog trainer I got,
he sent me a pricing menu, and he
was fucking expensive.
His cheapest package was like $1,000.
And I was like, "Oh, wow.
This guy's sick."
I'd even met him, already respected him,
saw what I was going to get, saw all the
things I needed, picked the package
that was right, boom.
So there's a loose format
that we need to follow for a landing page.
And again, if you've got your pen
and paper, write this down.
What it is,
what they get,
why they need it. What it is,
what they get, why they
need it,
why to trust you, how to pay.
That's it.
Now, the things that we need above that:
header, title, and a
subheading. Now, the header isn't
"How to lose fat and be in the shape of
your life forever." Too
generic. We need something
that really [growls] .
Get so fit, your ex wants you back.
Maybe not.
But I once had a header on a paid ad in
Sydney that said, "Wouldn't it be nice to
have more than your face in your Tinder
picture?" Now, that was polarizing, but it
worked. So we need a heading,
just a promise of what you do and,
how to stop smoking without cravings.
Whatever it is. Then a subheading
that just gives a bit of context
and nuance.
Next thing, you've got to put a VSL. Now,
VSL is a video sales letter.
Now, if you click the link to this
offer.
Have I got an offer on this social?
Let's have a little look. Maybe.
Maybe I've got an offer.
Well,
if you go to the business mentorship page,
let's say.
If you go to that page, you will see
that you go heading, title, then we've got
VSL. A video sales letter
is just a two to three-minute video
explaining what it
is. Now, we don't need fancy editing.
We just need to go, "Hi,
welcome to my business mentorship.
Two years ago,
I started working with hundreds of
businesses to help them navigate
through the online world of getting sales
online without having to spend hours each
day in DMs or having to beg people to jump
on sales calls." Blah.
Some people go on a landing page
and just watch the video.
Some people go on, just read the text.
Some people go on, analyze every word.
Some people go through, skim it.
We need a page that works for everyone.
So what is it?
Tell them it's a mentorship.
Tell them it's an online community.
Tell them there's a Discord where you can
interact on a daily basis.
What they get,
you get access to a load of resources
and courses that I've created
on email marketing, landing pages,
et cetera. Why you need it.
Because you're currently winging it,
and I've been doing this for 10 years.
You can save yourself all the frustrations
and time that I've wasted.
Why to trust me? Now, why to trust me?
You can use the money-back guarantee,
or you can use testimonials,
and then how to
pay.
Ultimately, for me,
the sales calls I hate because I don't
want any feedback of failed
attempts.
I've said this before. If I'm on Hinge,
I do not want to see
all the people that said no to me.
I just don't.
After this webinar,
I will only see the money come in my bank
account and the
people that joined. That's it.
That's all I care about.
If I was to open up my diary for sales
calls, I could make way more money, but
I'd rather be poorer,
to be perfectly honest.
I look at that Brian Mark, and I met him,
and he's actually quite a nice guy.
And I'm pretty sure his business does more
than me.
I don't know if he's making more profit
because he's still wearing a G-Shock.
I'm just going to throw that out there.
You're doing a million a month, bro,
you're wearing a G-Shock.
Make that make sense.
I know you're Canadian,
but I can't make that make sense.
If you said, "James,
you can make double the amount
of money, but do sales calls," I'll say,
"Keep it."
Keep it. Not interested. I'm a stubborn
piece of shit for that reason.
I have to love what I'm doing on a daily
basis, and
the idea of getting declined
or spending time with people for them
not to buy for more money, yeah, no,
I'm not doing that.
So for me,
I think you just give people an option
or give them a money-back
guarantee. For some of you guys,
we did just put a block together for James
Smith Academy, but we give them a
one-month money-back guarantee.
So someone in three
and a half months can ask for their money
back. Why?
Because that's the way I sell.
I'd rather just say to someone--
Or here's one for
you. Nootonic,
we've done seven figures a month for the
last two months in a row,
and a lot of that probably stemmed from
the fact that I've said,
if you don't love,
and I'm saying this to you right now,
anyone watching this, UK, USA, Australia,
for
the creatine. If you buy Nootonic
and you don't love it,
I'll refund your in full.
Cool.
I've just taken away loads of
apprehensions you might have had about it.
Do you know how many refunds I had to do
for Black Friday in November?
Zero.
Over a million dollars in revenue,
zero refunds.
What did it do to our sales rate?
Probably positively impacted it.
So just because you offer a guarantee
doesn't mean that people
are going to take it
up. People aren't dickheads.
Now,
one thing I would say for a landing page,
and get your questions in if you
want. For the landing page,
if you've got two different offers,
create two
different landing pages.
I've got a landing page for Send Emails
Get Paid.
I've got a landing page for Content
Mastery.
I've got a landing page for Business
Mentorship.
I created a fucking squeeze page just for
this webinar.
And every page you have should only have
one focus.
A landing page is to get a sale.
A squeeze page is to get an email.
Do not conflate the two.
Do not get it confused.
Now, some of you will need calls.
So let's say you're an accountancy firm
and a client to you is worth 10 grand
a year. Get on a call with them.
Let's say you're a wills
and probate lawyer
and you need to talk someone through
their family structures and see whether
or not a will is going to work for them
with their business structure.
Get on a call with them. Fine.
If you are a mortgage advisor
and you know that once you get on the
phone with
someone,
they're going to be using you for the
mortgage, get on the phone with
them. But if you're a personal trainer,
if you're a physio,
just fucking tell them to buy.
Just get your first month up front
and offer a fat
money-back guarantee. Because
if you're not shit at your job,
you'll be fine.
We
tested sales calls for this program.
Didn't rate it.
Just offer a fat guarantee.
Okay. Let's have a look at your questions.
Let's have a little look.
You talk about not having a brand name as
your handle.
What happens if you're known for
that name,
like Postman's Par? I don't know. Yours
is The Postman's Par.
Postman's Par. Let's have a little look,
shall we? Let's have a little look.
Postman's Par, what is that?
I can't find you on socials
when I put that.
Postman's Par. Let me Google it.
What is Postman's Par?
I see Postman's Park.
Well, that goes to show how good
that brand name is.
Can't seem to find you.
You could transition, mate.
Ed Lawrence was Film Booth, then he
was Creator Booth.
The only thing that I disagreed with Ed on
was that he should be the brand name,
and then he's changed it, like two, three,
four years into it, whatever it is.
So like, mate, I was JS Training,
then I was James Smith Training,
then I was James
Smith Fat Loss Coach and Educator.
Now I'm James Smith.
Chris Williamson was Modern Wisdom.
If you go to his YouTube now,
he's changed it to Chris Williamson.
So it's never too late, mate.
And let's think about it this
way.
Let's say you rebrand from Postman's Par,
which I don't know what that means,
to David Cooper.
No one's going to go, "Oh, David,
you fucking dickhead.
You're The Postman's Par.
I'm unfollowing you, brother.
I'm unfollowing you.
I'm unfollowing you because argh."
They go, "Oh, cool.
I get it." I couldn't find you there,
mate. I couldn't.
I don't know what Postman's Par is.
Catherine Sargent, how are you, you fox?
I've got loads of new leads on email list
and recently have a new course to sell.
Should I exclude the new followers from
emails selling my course so they don't
arrive and feel sold to? No.
Is this the Chin Up course?
So for any of you out there,
Catherine Sargent, OG, two years in
the mentorship.
About a year ago,
I shared her to the business page stories,
and my caption was,
"You deserve more followers." And
that didn't really do much
for you. It didn't.
I know it didn't because I watched.
And it goes to show my influence isn't as
strong as I thought.
But now I go to your page, 42,000 likes.
Nothing makes me happier.
And I think everyone can say this as well
inside the mentorship.
We're all so happy for this because you've
achieved a lot in
your life
You
won't mind me saying this,
become a bit of a fox in your 40s,
and you can put all
the boys to shame with the amount of
chin-ups you can do.
And you're so good at doing chin-ups
that you can explain how to do them whilst
doing them. And people
that have tried copying your content
are out of
breath and shaking like a shitting dog.
So fair play for that. Now,
you're worried that new people
are going to join the email list
and feel sold to.
I would say this,
for that case,
let's put the sales part as a PS.
So I want an amazing email journey,
personal journey,
anecdote, experience.
I want you to go through your camera roll,
whatever it
is,
and I want you to share that. Then PS,
if you want to work with me and buy this
program, you can go here. PS,
I appreciate a lot of you are new,
so I'm not going
to sell too much. Go here.
So do not exclude it,
just move it further down.
What I'd love is an email of your own
journey
where you lost weight,
but then I'd love another one where you
could even go
back 12 months and go, "12 months ago,
none of you followed me,
none of you were on my email list.
I was
just a mum putting out content in my spare
time,
and now I'm here because I didn't give
up." And you could then
talk about all the internal dialogues
and struggles you had thinking it would
never
work, and now it works.
You could go through all those little
things, then go,
"Look, I appreciate where you are.
It doesn't feel like you could ever do a
chin-up.
A year ago,
it would never feel like I would ever have
a following on social media,
but things change, things progress.
Your journey could be like mine.
Here's the program." PPS,
if you're not ready to buy yet,
completely fine.
I'm going to win you over, cheekily,
over the next whatever it is.
Jay, "I have my landing pages
and do my email marketing through
GoHighLevel and
thinking keep it all in one place.
Thoughts on GHL to others?" Never used it,
mate,
to be perfectly honest.
I quite like having things in different
places. I do.
Because I use different marketing.
I use SendGrid for my app.
I use Klaviyo for the business mentorship.
I use Mailchimp for James Smith Media.
So I've got things in different places.
I don't mind is what I would say.
What annoys me with GoHighLevel
is, in my head,
it should be Go Higher Level,
not GoHighLevel.
GoHighLevel to me just doesn't sit right
grammatically.
But anyway. Thomas,
"Do you recommend multiple posts per day
or one good
post per day enough?"
Well, imagine this. We're in a boxing
match.
I'm going to probably score more
if I strike more. That's it.
If I'm like, "Right,
I'm just going to do 10 punches this
match," it's not going to
go well. If I do 20 punches,
probably going to do better.
And if you watch boxing combinations,
sometimes it's one
that you don't anticipate
that makes it through.
So I don't really understand your
question.
You should be putting out as much content
as physically possible
without burning out. And
if that's several posts a day, cool.
And if it's not, cool.
But you shouldn't just be like,
"What's better, one or two posts a day?"
You are in a hyper-competitive
marketplace, and there are people out
there like me who are psychopaths,
who will sit on a live stream for two
hours
on a Monday morning without even going for
a piss to win business.
I'm here whilst my competitors
are going to bed.
I'm here. I'm crazy, mate.
I'll do anything to win business.
I'm super competitive. And
if you just want to post once a day,
fine,
because that'll be me posting two fitness
videos a day, one
YouTube on my business account,
and a live stream in the same day.
And I'll still have time to go get my
semen analysis done, which I'm doing for
another project I'm working on for another
new business that I'm starting.
There are levels to this, brother, and
if you just want to do once a day, that's
cool,
but you will never beat psychos like me
that don't stop.
And I'm going to train jujitsu,
and I'm going to tap out some
motherfuckers, and
I'm going to squeeze in a nap,
and I'm going to smash my misses.
I don't stop, bro.
So you, if you want to do one a day,
that's fine.
But there are some people out there
that just aren't right in the head,
and I'm one
of them.
And if you want a chance of competing with
me, I need better attitude than
that. I need you to go,
"I'm going to post as much as
physically possible without developing a
fucking mental disorder." Now I'm like,
"Yeah,
now you're talking." Because success in
business,
it is a bit of a mental disorder.
You've got to train yourself to be okay
with it.
It's a crazy 10,
20 years you've got ahead of you, and
it takes a certain temperament to do it.
So when you hear, "One good post
or two shit posts a day," I'm like, "Are
we on the same frequency,
bro?" Don't be asking stuff like that.
All right?
Off The Pine PT. That brand's got to go.
That brand's got to go.
What does Off The Pine mean?
Or am I an idiot?
"I have staff for my PT business.
Do I post on my business page content
that's
just me or do it on my personal?
I have staff for my PT business,
do I post on my
business?" What are you posting for?
What's the outcome?
Are you trying to get more clients for
those? I don't really understand that.
Let's have a little look on Insta.
Off The Pine PT.
Is this like a golf thing
or something that I don't know?
Off The Pine PT.
All right, I find you.
57 followers.
"Training that holds up
when life doesn't."
You're in Canberra. Bro, you got 19 posts,
57 followers.
I'm not sure what we're asking here.
You've got staff for PT.
What are you trying to sell?
Because I don't know.
I went on your page then.
I gave you more than enough time.
John Brown,
"All my sales come from Instagram DMs."
Wow.
"Currently have no email list.
Do you recommend doing both
or all in on email
list?"
Imagine this, mate.
[coin dropping] I've been there.
I've been there.
Back in the day,
I remember walking on a treadmill in Bondi
Fitness First,
and I followed 1,500 people.
I found Sydney's
biggest gyms,
and I manually followed all the people
that were members of them, and
I thought, "If I follow 3,000 people
and 300 people follow me back,
cool.
I might
grow my following." I've been there.
But I'm just going to throw this out
there.
DM-ing people for business,
it's not sustainable. It's not.
And you want to build an email list
because right
now, mate,
what if I said
In a few years' time,
you can just send one message
and it goes to thousands of
people. That's email marketing.
So you're having to give your energy
and effort to
one person to get one sale.
I get depressed if 125,000 people don't
open my email on a daily
basis. 125,000. That's scale.
And guess what?
My work, 1,000 opens, 10,000 opens,
100,000
opens, is the same. For you, your work per
person can't scale. So ultimately,
you're doing it manual,
you're doing it the hard way.
When you say,
"All my sales come from DMs," I look at
you and go, "Your marketing
is pathetic." But it's okay,
because you can get pathetic gains for the
time
being. You need an email list,
or all of your competitors at the same age
as you, doing the same thing, will get
an email list,
and they will start to dominate you.
They're going to wake up
in the Maldives, open their laptop,
send an email, close the laptop,
get on with
their day. And you're going to be there,
"Oh, sorry, babe.
Yeah, just one second, babe. Sorry,
I've just got to get back to some DMs."
"Oh,
sorry, babe, it's business." "Oh, sorry,
babe, I'm working."
So, here's one for you as well.
Last week I was ill.
I had to cancel the webinar because I
was ill.
I was fucked for eight days,
and still trained jujitsu,
still made crazy amounts of revenue,
but I just didn't fancy being in front of
camera. Some days, all I did
was just send an email.
I don't even do my own DMs. Actually,
I've just got someone to run DMs in my
main account,
because I don't look at them.
There are so many people on the edge of
buying my stuff in the DMs, I've just
appointed someone in the DMs.
So you should hire someone to do the DMs
for
you.
You can find someone in the Philippines
who's fucking good, and you should
start focusing on an email list.
But think about it this way,
anyone that's good at what they do,
doesn't beg for business in the
DMs. Let's say I need a lawyer.
[chuckles] I need a lawyer,
it's really important.
I'm not going to hope they fucking sell to
me in the DMs.
Let's say I need a wedding photographer.
It's just not going to be a DM sales kind
of thing.
Tell me the problems you're facing.
Instagram DM should be for getting pussy,
sending memes,
and abusing your mates.
Nothing in between.
Sana, "What do you think you do
if your target client
is too embarrassed to comment
on your posts,
and they don't reply to email articles
or get on survey
calls to give feedback to my offer?"
What's a survey call?
Too embarrassed to comment on your post.
You have a landing page they can go to,
right?
Because it's not about embarrassment,
They should have a funnel they can go
through. They should see you on socials.
If they have the opportunity to be part of
a squeeze, they should.
It could be commenting on a post,
but you can also say, "DM me the word,"
if they
want to keep it private.
Then they go to your email marketing list,
then they get
sent to a landing page.
I don't see why embarrassment would be an
issue.
Also,
you can even say to people tongue in
cheek, "Comment, then delete it." That
works as well.
Off The Pine PT.
"I run my own personal training business,
Off The Pine Personal
Training." What does that mean,
by the way, Off The Pine?
"I have staff and a good local brand
awareness.
Shall I post on that on my personal page?"
Oh,
Shannon McKenzie PT.
Hold on. I went to Off The Pine, there
was nothing there.
What does this mean?
Shannon McKenzie PT.
The same thing. I can't find you.
I'm on social media, I can't find you.
So
you're asking me what page should I post
off.
I don't know what it is
or what you're doing.
I don't understand.
If you have a personal page
and a business page,
if you need to grow the business,
you might post on the business,
but even then,
I'd probably still do it on the
personal. Like I say, people
are drawn to personal brands at the
moment,
not to businesses.
If you look at Score App,
does well because of Daniel Priestley.
Acquisition.com does well because of Alex
Hormozi.
Modern Wisdom does well because of Chris
Williamson.
Diary of a CEO and fucking Perfect Ted do
well because of Steven Bartlett.
The thing you want at the front of the
figurehead is a person to represent the
business.
So yeah. We're there.
Right. I have a question for you lot.
The course is 2,499 US dollars.
How many clients would you need
to win back to earn that back?
And any of you that are in my mentorship,
if
you don't mind, just for one minute,
just give me some feedback for other
people to
see here. I've been here for an hour
and 47 minutes.
All I'm going to ask
is you give me one more minute to look at
what people that
work with me say, if there
are any still here.
$2,500 is a lot, I get that. But
if I charge half, I
have twice the amount of people in.
If I have twice the amount of people in,
I don't know you.
I don't know you first name basis.
I don't know if you've got daughters
or sons.
I don't know where you live.
When I see you at an event,
I don't know who the fuck
you are. At the price point it's at,
when I see you at an event, I go,
"I know who you are.
I've seen your fucking landing page."
When I was at my Sydney event, I was like,
"Sammy,
sort your fucking landing page colors out.
Ryan,
you're making too much money." Whatever it
is.
The more expensive I go,
the more of me you get.
So that's why the price is what it is.
And it's still grossly undercharged as it
is.
Everything I teach
is in line with getting you more sales
with doing less, and it's all based around
the premise of getting leads to come to
you.
I would never tell you to do something
that I wouldn't do
myself. And when you join,
you should notice that then you
start to see all the things I do on social
media, and you start to see it all come
together.
You start to see the binary code in the
matrix start to work.
So you've got an offer there,
2,499,
and here's a guarantee I'll give you.
If within three months
you can prove to me you've done what I
said and it hasn't worked,
I'll refund you.
There it is.
But if you cry and you haven't done any of
the things that I've told you to do,
then we're going to have a dispute.
Then I'm going to argue with you over
email.
It's 2,499.
We're probably going to take on about 100
more people, which seems like a lot, but
I've got a couple of staff now.
It's either going to work,
or I'll refund you.
We're going into January
It's a very important time for your
businesses.
We've skimmed over quite a lot of these
things today.
I'm actually also rebuilding the entire
course out in
January and February. With everything
that I'm learning from working with all
the
businesses, Mentorship 3.0
is going to get built in the next few
months.
You get lifetime access to all of the
courses.
There's a YouTube course that's getting
added
before the next price rise.
We've also kept the prices down for this
webinar and
pushed it back a week.
The YouTube course
is probably worth about two grand in
itself. So,
yeah.
There's the offer. There it is.
Link's in the description.
Even if you don't leave, even
if you don't join right now, guess what?
I'm still going to fucking email you the
offer because I've got your email address,
I've earned the fucking goodwill,
I'm going to hammer the fuck out of your
email
inbox,
and I'm going to hit you with so many
emotive reasons that you
should join that I'm going to prove to you
exactly why this works.
And just remember, I didn't come to you,
you came to me.
You're now being sold to.
You came to my sales pitch.
You're getting the fucking offer, and
if you buy, I find out about it.
If you don't, I don't. This
is the 4S James
Smith Socials
Squeeze Sell Scale Formula in
action. [claps] Gosh.
You've come straight into the honey trap.
I want to teach you how to set these honey
traps everywhere else for other people.
It's been enjoyable.
I could go for another two hours
if you wanted me to,
but yeah.
I do honestly appreciate all of you giving
me the time.
I don't want to waste your money,
and I'll be perfectly honest with you.
I'll take the presenter mode off for a
second.
If you genuinely come to me
and what I've taught you hasn't worked,
I don't deserve
your money.
Fair enough. That's it.
But I'm going to keep the offer there.
I'm going to keep this video up,
probably for a while for you guys to check
in. But yeah.
I give a lot of time and energy into this.
I won't let you down like the other
fucking mentorships. I'm hypercompetitive.
I wouldn't let this be shit.
It would keep me awake at night.
So thank you very much for tuning in,
and I'll see you guys soon.
And
if you can't be good, be careful.
Click the link in the bio. See you later.
Up the bum, no babies.